[{"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Workplace culture is important to us at Company ABC. What type of work environment do you dislike working in?", "answers": ["Are you pretty flexible in your ability to work in most environments? Have you experienced a position where the atmosphere wasn't conducive to your productivity?  Be sure to know the type of environment that is offered by Company ABC, before the interview.", "\"I can be productive in most work environments, so long as the mentality is positive and teamwork is encouraged. I cannot work in an environment that feels negative or toxic.\"", "Rather than focusing on the negative, try spinning your answer into a positive focus: \"I do best in a supportive environment where there is room to grow, the ability to ask questions, and healthy co-worker relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire problem solvers. When were you able to resolve a workplace related problem?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are critical skills to possess. Display to the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace and that you will do so with Company ABC.", "\"In my most recent position we had a consistent problem with employees showing up late for their shifts or calling in sick at the very last moment. Rather than the typical documenting and reprimanding style that management usually takes, I decided to track the results of an accountability reward system. For 180 days, my employees were rewarded for coming to work 10 minutes early. Also, for every month with zero sick days, a bonus was added. In the end, we awarded those with perfect attendance a $600 bonus. The bonus' cost us less money, in the end than the cost of lowered productivity due to absent employees. The program was a success, and upper management chose to keep it implemented for another six months. We will re-assess in December, but it seems to be working very well.\"", "\"I often solve small problems in the workplace related to merchandising. I am often researching new merchandising techniques to push out some of the older merchandise, to make room for the new.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Tell me something about yourself that I wouldn't know from reading your resume.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you apart from what is written on your resume. You are certainly not obligated to discuss personal matters such as your kids, or relationship status, for instance. Stick with a couple of fun facts to show the interviewer that you are a real person, too. Your answer should be unique so that you are a memorable candidate for Company ABC!  \n\nFocus on special non-work related skills or hobbies.  For example, you might share that you enjoy beat-boxing or making origami swans. Be prepared for the interviewer to stop you and ask you to perform your skill on the spot when its possible! (This will make you unforgettable!)", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit.\"", "\"I recently completed a computer programming course that I have not had a chance to add to my resume yet. I enjoy continued education and will take multiple courses throughout the year.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We seek to hire ambitious and dedicated people at Company ABC. What is your definition of hard work?", "answers": ["Hard work and dedication can be interpreted differently by everyone. To one person, another person's hard work could seem like slacking. Talk to the interviewer about how you interpret a successful workday.", "\"For me, hard work means that I did what I could that day to exceed expectations. I come to work early and stay late if needed and I go over and above the requirements without hesitation.\"", "\"I fully believe in the work smarter, not harder, motto. This means that I am efficient throughout the day, not allowing for distractions. Hard work means not only meeting the expectations of your employer but also exceeding them whenever possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Our industry is a competitive one. In your opinion, what makes Company ABC stand out from our competitors?", "answers": ["It is vital that you thoroughly research Company ABC before your interview, as well as their competitors. Be prepared to talk about their competitive landscape and why Company ABC comes out on top. You can keep your answer brief but be as specific as you can. Show off the research you've done!", "\"I fully understand that this is a competitive industry. You get one chance to impress your customers, so first impressions are everything. When I looked online at the industry reviews, Company ABC seemed to have many more positive reviews than any competitor. You say on your website that your customer service values are the most important focus and that truly does stand out.\"", "\"After researching Company ABC I think that the verbiage you use on your website and your social media content has the most positive and customer-centered message. That was a real stand out to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we are always looking for new ways of improving services. Do you have any suggestions for us?", "answers": ["The interviewer is indeed not asking you to reinvent their wheel. The worst thing you could do here is speak negatively about Company ABC without any constructive feedback. If you do have a suggestion, keep it light and be sure to close your answer on a complimentary, and positive note.", "\"I think that you are doing an impressive job at Company ABC and I look forward to coming to work with you. If I could make any suggestion, I would recommend more updates on the company blog. People are interested in what Company ABC has to say!\"", "\"I appreciate all of the hard work that Company ABC puts into the services and other creative solutions. My primary suggestion would be to include more digital downloads and worksheets related to your products on your company website. Customers greatly value free resources.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Tell me about a project you worked on where a conventional approach was not suitable.", "answers": ["How have you implemented creativity in the workplace when a conventional approach was not suitable? Display for the hiring manager how you can think outside of the box when necessary.", "\"In 2009 our economy suffered, and a lot of businesses were struggling to keep their doors open. At that time, a conventional approach was to take out additional ads on the radio or TV. Social media was starting to become a major advertising outlet - and it was free. I launched a social media campaign that was very successful. We were able to generate new and repeat business while coming in under our advertising budget.\"", "\"I rarely take a conventional approach when it comes to my work. Conventional is often predictable and predictable does not equal great sales numbers.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Would you say you are a better verbal or written communicator?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know more about your strengths when it comes to communication in the workplace. Discuss your preference with the interviewer, and support your answer.", "\"I prefer verbal communication because I feel that with written communication, a lot can be misread due to lack of tone, fluctuation, expression and body language. I will always choose a face to face conversation whenever possible.\"", "\"Being a millennial, I have grown up always preferring written communication via email, or text message. With that said, I am a strong verbal communicator as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face issues. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you have the ability to see opportunity when others can only focus on the problem. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creative side. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I am a great problem solver because I am very analytically minded. I will walk through each step to a problem so that I can properly calculate any available options.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Working at Company ABC can become stressful from time to time. How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted.\"", "\"Staying on deadline is very helpful for me, under stressful situations. I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["This question can be tricky because it requires you to know enough about Company ABC to be impressed by what they do, and what they have to offer. \n\nPrepare for this question through due diligence! Review the company website first. If Company ABC is more service or client focused, you can read reviews of customers and find out about their reputation. Sometimes you can even find articles or press releases to give you a brief on their latest accomplishments, innovations or company culture. Pinpoint the highlights. \n\nKnow the company vision so that you can quickly tell them that your values align. Sharing your knowledge on the latest company related news is a great indicator that you have a vested interest in them.", "\"I am impressed by your mission, and I love how much of an impact you make on the local community. Winning the community Humanitarian Award in 2016 was a remarkable achievement that stands out to me.\"", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because you offer the growth, development, and leadership opportunities I have been looking for. I see a long-term fit here which is important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with setbacks in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"I feel that most setbacks are directly related to missing a particular detail along the way. When I suffer a setback, my initial instinct is to go back through my project and find the weak link. This way, I can learn from the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We value our customers at Company ABC. How do you respond to customer or client complaints?", "answers": ["If you are interviewing for a customer or client facing role, you want to show off your ability to deal with conflict and nurture client relationships. Give an example of a time you successfully helped resolve a customer's issue.", "\"A customer called me very frustrated about a problem with one of our software products. I listened and told them I would be happy to help. I asked more questions to understand the problem and then suggested once I had a better idea of what might solve it. The customer was very relieved and grateful that I took the time to listen and make sense of the issue.\"", "\"I recently completed a course on customer service and dispute resolution, so I am confident in my ability to handle client related issues. Active listening and genuine empathy is always the backbone of my approach with customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Company ABC is looking for reliable people. How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the nose. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2, and a note from my Doctor accompanied those. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm, and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I am very committed to my employer and am only absent in events of sickness or the odd family emergency. I do my best always to be available and present when expected.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "If we hire you at Company ABC, how can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are being noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"I am very much self-driven and self-motivated. As long as I am being treated with respect and feel appreciated, Company ABC will get the best work from me.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We prefer that employees at Company ABC have some form of post-secondary education. Walk me through your education and how you feel it has prepared you for this role.", "answers": ["You likely have your post-secondary education listed on your resume; however, the interviewer would like further details on your accomplishments, or experience in general. \n\nPerhaps you graduated top of your class! Did you receive any special accolades or recognition during your time in post-secondary studies? You can also discuss a course that you found intriguing.", "\"I have a Degree in Computer Engineering from DeVry University. I felt very prepared after earning my degree because the classes were incredibly hands on. I was able to learn a great deal about business management as well. These are all skills I feel would help me greatly in this position with Company ABC. Even though I worked part-time through my studies at DeVry, I was still able to earn excellent marks and graduate top of my class. I would bring the same level of engagement and enthusiasm to this role.\"", "\"I understand that Company ABC prefers hiring those with formal post-secondary education. Although I have not completed my degree, my seven years of related experience has given me a great deal of knowledge. I am prepared for this role because my current employer has allowed me to take many courses and workshops related to our industry. This year I have taken additional training in A, B, and C.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "If you are hired at Company ABC you may become privy to trade secrets and confidential information. Are you willing to sign a non-disclosure agreement?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are willing to comply with their non-disclosure requirements before you start working for Company ABC. \n\nYour willingness to sign a non-disclosure agreement will tell the interviewer that you are not looking for a short-term employment situation where you can be frivolous with the knowledge that you gain. If you are not comfortable agreeing to sign a non-disclosure immediately, simply state your openness to reviewing the agreement.", "\"Yes, I am willing to take a look at your non-disclosure agreement. Most agreements are very reasonable and since I plan to work for Company ABC long-term - this is not a concern for me.\"", "\"I agree that non-disclosures are important in most industries and I am willing to sign one should I be hired at Company ABC\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we like to develop Subject Matter Experts (SME's) in multiple fields. If you could sum up your knowledge to one area of expertise, what would it be?", "answers": ["Everyone has their strengths and areas of expertise. The interviewer wants to know what your is. Talking about your strong suits is not bragging, but it can still be tough to pump your tires. Think about times in the recent past where your manager or co-workers have come to you for answers. Do you seem to have the answers when it comes to a particular subject? Perhaps you just completed additional education or certification in a specific area. Discuss an area where you think you bring above average industry knowledge.", "\"I have spent a few years sharpening my knowledge and expertise in X. In my current position, my coworkers will often come to me with questions relating to this subject. I am always happy to help, and if I do not know the answer, I will research until I have found one.\"", "\"If I could sum up my knowledge in one area of expertise, I would say that I am a subject matter expert in heavy duty electronics and equipment. I am very passionate about the subject. With that said, I do enjoy continued education in a range of subjects.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those with a strong understanding of the computer, IT, and electronics industry. Walk me through your background and highlight your most relevant experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer can see that you have previous positions which qualify you for this job with Company ABC; however, they want for you to go into further detail on the roles which you feel are the most relevant to the position at hand. This question also helps the interviewer to see that you understand the job description and requirements of the role. If you do not understand the position requirements fully, a question like this will make that transparent to the interviewer. Be sure you know your stuff! Use the keywords provided in the job posting/job description to keep the attention of the interviewer.", "\"From my understanding of this position, you are looking for a professional who is skilled in X, Y, and Z. I bring about seven years of experience in each of those skills - primarily from my jobs with Company A and Company B. In total; I have over ten years of industry experience which means a full understanding of your organizations' primary focus.\"", "\"I feel that my current position is the most relevant to this particular role with Company ABC because we use the same software, and the business model is very similar. My current position aside, I have approximately ten years of related experience in skills A, B, and C - which you mentioned as required skills for this position.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We have multiple avenues for career growth. Where would you like to see your career with Company ABC take you?", "answers": ["Interviewing, hiring, and onboarding is an expensive and time-consuming process for Company ABC. Since there are likely many career opportunities available to you at Company ABC, be prepared to discuss how you would like to see your career grow. This shows the interviewer that you are engaged in this process and interested in becoming a long-term fixture in their organization.", "\"I was browsing your online job board to see what types of growth opportunities were available with Company ABC. One role that stood out to me was the IT Department Manager position. It seemed that this could be a very natural step in my career once I have grown with you for a couple of years. I'd like to learn more about what I can do to prepare myself for a role like that.\"", "\"In my current position, I have had my sights set on the senior leadership position in my department. If I were to join Company ABC, my goal would be the same. I plan to take a few leadership workshops in the coming months to help get me there.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "As you know, we have a very high customer service standard at Company ABC. If you could sum up your customer service style in 3 words, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Most companies rely heavily on their customer service reputation. Assure the interviewer that you will value their client base by providing the same excellent service they have come to expect from Company ABC. \n\nWhen using keywords to describe your customer service style try to avoid overused terms such as 'friendly'. If there are keywords you see frequently used by Company ABC on their website, in their job postings, or in their job descriptions, you can draw on those as well.", "\"I have heard great things about the customer service provided by Company ABC and I look forward to joining your esteemed team. If I could sum up my customer service style in 3 words, I would choose attentive, personalized, and energetic.\"", "Here are some traits that many hiring managers look for when determining your ability to provide great service to their clients: \n\n- Ability to Handle The Unexpected \n- Attentive\n- Calming\n- Communicative\n- Confident \n- Intuitive\n- Knowledgeable \n- Patient\n- Persuasive \n- Positive / Positive Language and Outlook\n- Timely"]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Clear and simple communication is a must-have in our industry. Tell me about your communication skills.", "answers": ["When you are working with more complex products and services, it is imperative that you simplify your communication. Talk to the interviewer about your communication style and how it will benefit the goals of Company ABC.", "\"I understand that Company ABC has built a culture of openness where your teams can bounce ideas off of each other. My communication style fits well with this. I put a lot of effort into keeping my communication style simple, engaging, and to the point. I enjoy collaborating with my team and participating in positive brainstorming sessions.\"", "Here are some communication-related keywords that you can use when discussing your communication skills: \n\n- Adaptable\n- Balanced\n- Clear\n- Decisive\n- Energetic\n- Fresh\n- Helpful\n- Logical\n- Mature\n- Open\n- Powerful\n- Relaxed\n- Sincere\n- Tasteful\n- Upbeat"]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Do you have any questions for me about this role, or working for Company ABC?", "answers": ["When the interviewer asks if you have any questions, you should always have at least one. By asking a question, big or small, you are showing the interviewer that you have insight, a thoughtful character and that you are engaged in this process. \n\nDo not ask questions about compensation, days off, sick days, benefits, or the like. Your question should be related to your fit for the position. Take this opportunity to find any potential objections to an employment offer, and squash them!", "\"I feel that you have given me a strong understanding of the requirements for this role and I thank you for that. Are there any hesitations when it comes to my suitability for this position?\"", "Other questions you could ask include: \n\n- Can I clarify anything for you about my background?\n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me for this role?\n- When are you hoping to have this position filled?\n- What is your favorite part of working with Company ABC?"]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"Although my current salary is $45K/year, I am seeking $52K in my next position. Because I work for a very small organization, they are not able to offer me a competitive compensation compared to the industry marketplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "What do you think our biggest business challenge is at Company ABC, and how will you help?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that you have more to offer than just a warm body in a seat! What is this particular company's biggest challenge, and how do you think that you can assist? This question requires research on Company ABC, their business goals, and the competitive landscape.", "\"After speaking with you further about Company ABC, and this role, I believe that the biggest challenge this company has faced is in hiring the right talent. I have a strong background in recruitment as well as management and do feel that I can assist with this hurdle. Having the right team players is imperative to a company's success and, if we can tackle that, I see great things happening.\"", "\"When I applied to Company ABC I knew exactly which gaps I would be able to help fill. I want to assist with refreshing your sales strategy. I would also like to help train your new hires to make a stronger impact on your clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We value honesty at Company ABC. Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem. In reality, honesty isn't always best expressed in full. I believe it can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"I do think that it's best to be completely honest in as many situations as possible. I understand there are some times when telling the full truth will not help either party but, for the most part, I do agree that honesty is the best policy.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "We have a strong team culture at Company ABC. How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"I like to encourage ideas in others by holding brainstorm or storyboarding sessions with my team at least once per month. When employees feel involved and heard, morale is always higher.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Do you think it is possible to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can be diplomatic in the workplace, even when you may not agree with your leader. \n\nShow the interviewer that it is possible for you to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader from time to time. Explain that you believe everyone is entitled to their own professional opinion, yet capable of maintaining respect for each other at the same time. \n\nShow that even if you disagree with the final decision they make, you support the direction the team is heading.", "\"I think that it is possible to be a great team member, even when disagreeing with the leader. It's all in how you maintain respect for each other despite the difference in opinion.\"", "\"I do try my best to be a great team member, regardless of whether or not I agree with the leader. With that said, it's important to me that I see eye to eye with my leader.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Have you ever taken the fall for a situation, where it was really not your fault, in order to protect a coworker?", "answers": ["Taking the fall for a situation, to protect a co-worker, is a tricky situation. It can show teamwork, but it may not be the most honest thing to do. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on taking the fall for something you did not do.", "\"I do not believe in 'taking the fall' for people based on protecting them. Transparency is always a good idea, and if something went wrong, then it needs to be addressed to prevent it from happening again. When it comes to clients, I will apologize on behalf of the company for errors. In that case, I will do what it takes to protect the company's reputation.\"", "\"I have taken the heat for a situation that was not my fault. Honestly, it wasn't anyone's fault, and I understand that sometimes the blame needs to land somewhere when corporate is looking for answers.\""]}, {"topic": "Computers+and+Electronic+Equipment", "question": "Do you demonstrate leadership qualities even when you are not in a leadership role?", "answers": ["This question challenges you to think about how you act as a leader in your daily life. Even if you're not leading a team, you can still demonstrate the qualities of a leader! \n\nGive an example of how you coached a coworker who was having difficulty preparing for a big presentation. Maybe you gave them confidence in their strengths by encouraging them, or maybe you offered some helpful hints. You can be a motivator and a positive communicator in any situation at work!", "\"I naturally take on a leader and mentorship type of role with my co-workers. In one instance, I had a new coworker who was having some troubles fitting in. I took her out for lunch and talked to her a bit about the workplace culture and semantics surrounding the various departments. I wanted her to stay and enjoy her employment with us, so I took the responsibility of ensuring she was settling in well. I believe there are always opportunities for leadership - you just have to keep your eyes open!\"", "\"Yes, I do demonstrate leadership qualities every chance that I get! I believe that everyone can be a great leader if given the right environment and opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "What do you believe to be Company ABC's strengths and weaknesses?", "answers": ["Your answer to this question will further display your knowledge of Company ABC overall, the areas in which it excels and those where there is room for growth. A good understanding of these aspects tells the hiring manager that, if hired, you will 'hit the ground running'. Mention how you think you can contribute to developing the Company ABC's perceived weaknesses to become strengths, thereby building it to be a stronger industry competitor overall.", "\"With data analytics needs increasing across companies, a growing number of competitors are entering the Data Analytics industry as service and product providers. Due to this increased competition, Company ABC will need to differentiate itself from the increasing number of players. Company ABC has a strong presence with its products, but I believe it has room to grow in its service offerings. This area is one where it can differentiate itself, and I believe, through my experience in the customer service industry, I can generate some valuable ideas to help Company ABC become a strong competitor.\"", "\"Data analytics needs vary across industries and companies.  Customization options are vital to meet a client's specific needs quickly and easily. Creating a customized product for each client is not feasible given limited resources. I am convinced that Company ABC continuously meets the specific needs of its clients, but believe that it can do so more economically and efficiently by improving product customization options. My experience working with external clients can help develop the customization options for Company ABC's products.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "We take pride in our company culture. Which aspect of the Company ABC culture do you find most attractive?", "answers": ["The hiring manager wants to ensure you are a good fit with the company and its culture. Your answer can also be an indication of what you value most when considering your place of employment. At times it may be difficult to get a clear picture of a company's culture through its website. A thorough internet search may reveal some employee reviews of Company ABC. Also, utilize your network to gather details on Company ABC's company culture.", "\"The value Company ABC places on training and education was something that attracted me to the company. This offering indicates to me that Company ABC values its employees and understands that they play a key role in the success of the company. I believe when employees feel valued, they are more likely to remain loyal to a company.\"", "\"I was pleasantly surprised by Company ABC's dedication to the community. By giving employees the opportunity to take time out of their workday to give back to the community, Company ABC shows that it respects the larger world we live in, beyond the company walls. Too many times companies are only concerned about profits. It's refreshing to see Company ABC encourage its employees to give their time to worthwhile causes. I believe it helps employees have a positive view of their job and their employer.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Company ABC fully appreciates the value of employee training. Describe your learning style. Do you prefer online training or learning in a classroom setting?", "answers": ["These days, to meet budgets and time constraints, training comes in a variety of formats. Companies are still relying on classroom or seminar style training, but online learning formats are becoming more common so employees can learn at a time that is most convenient for them. If you are more comfortable with online training, be sure to point out the positives of it while emphasizing that you appreciate the need for face-to-face communications. There is some criticism that online training isolates employees and prevents them from sharing their views and learning from one another.", "\"I prefer to receive online training because it allows me to learn at a time that is convenient for me. It also allows me to complete the training at my own pace to ensure that I understand the concepts presented. If there is a particular concept I do not understand well, I can pause the learning module to investigate it further using other resources. However, I think it is important to regularly gather with others in the company to share our knowledge and learn from one another.\"", "\"I believe I can learn more in a classroom setting.  Listening to an instructor in a live setting keeps me more engaged, and there are more learning opportunities as others in the classroom provide insights and opinions. It is important for the instructor or facilitator to keep the participants engaged through visual aids and lively discussion. Although attending a training session in a classroom may be less convenient than an online module, with proper planning, I do not believe it is too disruptive to my schedule.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "At Company ABC you would be working with multiple clients at a time. How will you meet everyone's needs?", "answers": ["The hiring manager is making it known which particular skills are highly valued at Company ABC. Mention past positions where you worked on multiple client projects, whether they were internal or external clients. In your answer, it will be important to highlight how organization and prioritization skills came into play and how these skills would help you manage client relationships while working at Company ABC.", "\"I wholeheartedly agree that organization and prioritization skills are important when dealing with clients. I have been fortunate enough to develop and strengthen these skills in my previous jobs. Organization skills helped me ensure that my clients' needs did not fall through the cracks, while prioritization skills helped me complete client projects quickly and efficiently. These same skills will be crucial while working with the projects for Company ABC's clients, particularly since Company ABC offers a wide variety of products and services and serves clients in a broad spectrum of industries.\"", "\"Organization and prioritization skills are undoubtedly vital in serving clients well by meeting their data analytics needs. In my past work experiences, I have found organization skills helped me work efficiently and therefore allowed me the ability to manage more client projects simultaneously over time without compromising the quality of work. Prioritization skills have allowed me to ensure that client projects were completed on time according to clients' specifications. I have found in the Data Analytics industry; timeliness is key as clients are always looking for answers to their strategic questions yesterday. I am confident that I will be able to apply these skills to strengthen relationships with Company ABC's clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC's competitive position within the data analytics industry?", "answers": ["This question will help the hiring manager gauge your knowledge of the industry and Company ABC. Knowing where Company ABC is positioned in the industry will prove you did your research. It will also confirm that you have a good understanding of the position for you which you are applying and the company overall. When speaking about the Company ABC's position in the industry, mention any niches Company ABC serves and its biggest competitors.", "\"The Data Analytics industry is constantly changing with new technology that makes tools more user-friendly. There is strong competition in this industry with companies continuously innovating to offer 'the next big thing' to their clients. Company ABC offers user-friendly interfaces that allow its products to be used across a client's company and not only by its data analysts, making data readily available to those who are looking for answers. I would say Company 1 and Company 2 are Company ABC's strongest competitors as their products strengths include a user-friendly interface highlighted in all marketing communications. Their goal of making data accessible to all parts of their clients' company is similar to that of Company ABC\"", "\"The Data Analytics industry has seen companies deal with massive amounts of data that are not being mined due to resource limitations. Also, data quality continues to be an issue as companies deal with vast amounts of data. Through its products and services, Company ABC understands these issues and implements solutions for them. With regards to competition, Company ABC faces companies such as Company1 and Company2 whose products and services also address these issues. Although Company ABC is not quite there yet in size and scope relative to these two competitors, it has increased its presence and has continued to establish itself as a growing threat.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "If you are offered a position at Company ABC, which of our products or services would you be most excited to work on, and why?", "answers": ["The ability to speak about one of Company ABC's products or services in depth will show the interviewer you did your research and prove your level of enthusiasm for the position. Be sure to research in detail a couple of Company ABC's products/services and what attracts you most to them. However, be sure to mention you are enthusiastic about the overall opportunity to work for Company ABC and that if you aren't assigned to the product(s)/service(s) you mentioned, it would not be a dealbreaker. Your answer to this question may also let the interviewer know where your specific interests may lie.", "\"Of your broad line of products and services, I would be most excited about working with the Company ABC's data mining and dashboard tools. I believe these tools allow for the most client customization and are built to meet clients' needs easily. Also, through my research, I have found that these tools have undergone vast improvements over the years using cutting-edge technology. It would be exciting working to help improve these tools each year. However, I believe Company ABC's overall innovative mindset will expose me to many exciting opportunities whether with these products or others.\"", "\"Company ABC's data visualization and modeling tools would be products I would be thrilled to work on. I have a great interest in helping develop ways to communicate client data visually. This approach will require creativity and innovation that I believe I have developed over the years. In addition, I think Company ABC's modeling tools are a powerful means for clients to get the most out of their data. Data modeling is a skill area I have always had a great interest in developing further. Although both of these products would present fulfilling opportunities, I am confident that all of Company ABC's products and services will provide learning and creative outlet opportunities for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "How will you contribute to the overall mission of Company ABC.", "answers": ["Do your research and have a strong understanding of Company ABC's overall mission.  Once you have a clear vision of that, thoughtfully consider how your skills and past experiences can help Company ABC achieve its goals and live out its overall mission. Be specific when talking about your skills and how you would be able to contribute, but do not get bogged down in too many details that may take you off track. Wait for the interviewer to ask follow-up questions before providing too many details.", "\"I believe my experience in the Data Analytics industry and my track record of customer service will help Company ABC fulfill its mission of providing high-quality products and services to its clients. I have an understanding of the types of products and services currently offered in the industry and therefore, have a clearer picture of how to make Company ABC's products and services more competitive and ultimately superior. Also, because of my previous work with clients in this industry, I am familiar with many of their general data analytics needs and requirements .\"", "\"Having worked in data analytics for companies in various industries, I have a strong understanding of what clients look for when it comes to Data Analytics services and products. Because I have a strong 'client perspective,' I believe I can contribute to Company ABC's overall mission of helping its clients build effective strategies supported by solid data analytics products and services. My most effective contribution to Company ABC's mission will be to build secure and long-lasting client relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "What made you decide to apply to Company ABC?", "answers": ["The hiring manager would like to know what attracted you to Company ABC and not just the posted job. Answering this question provides you the opportunity to show what you know about the Data Analytics industry and Company ABC's position in it. Through your answer, prove to the hiring manager you did your research carefully and know that Company ABC is the right company for you.", "\"My background is primarily in the Data Analytics field, and I have enjoyed working in this industry as it constantly undergoes change and growth. Through my research, I found Company ABC to be innovative and forward-thinking. I want to be part of a company that serves its clients with technologically advanced solutions.\"", "\"Although my experience in the Data Analytics industry is limited, I know it is continuously growing and changing. I am looking to work in an industry that presents on-going challenges and for a company that faces those challenges with unique and advanced solutions. I found that Company ABC has proven to be a company that is a serious competitor in this industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Our industry is becoming increasingly saturated. How do you think Company ABC stands out from its competitors?", "answers": ["Your answer to this question should show your knowledge of both the Data Analytics industry and the specific services and products offered by Company ABC. When researching this industry, be sure to familiarize yourself with Company ABC's direct competitors and the products and services they provide. Be prepared with at least 2-3 points of differentiation to display your knowledge of Company ABC and the industry.", "\"I believe customer service will always be a point of differentiation in a competitive industry such as Data Analytics. Based on my research, Company ABC prides itself in going above and beyond to understand its clients business and tailoring its products and services to meet their data analytics needs. Data analytics tools and solutions tend to be built as 'one-size-fits-all'. Many clients have unique requirements and Company ABC takes the necessary steps to understand and craft a solution for them.  Not many companies would take the time to do so.\"", "\"From my observation, Company ABC seems to be a strong innovator in the Data Analytics industry. Being an innovative company, Company ABC stays a step ahead of its competitors and shows its understanding of industry trends and the client needs. Company ABC has established itself as a leader, instead of a follower, in the Data Analytics industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Company ABC does its best to maintain strong relationships with its clients. How will you ensure our clients remain loyal?", "answers": ["Keeping clients satisfied and returning for additional products and services is key to the success of Company ABC. Your answer should communicate that you understand the importance of this. Think of one or two of your strongest skills and highlight how they can help maintain strong client relationships. Do you have an example illustrating how your skills aided in strengthening client relationships? Be sure to include that in your answer.", "\"I believe my problem-solving skills will be a strong asset in strengthening relationships with Company ABC's clients. These skills will allow me to work with the client to solve any data analytics issues they may be having. Clients will appreciate thorough and efficient solutions that will not stall their abilities to conduct business and build strategies. This approach creates value for clients, making it difficult for them to look elsewhere for their data analytics needs.\"", "\"My technical and communication skills have proven to be essential when working with clients. When trying to tailor products and services to meet a client's needs, my technical skills and knowledge have allowed me to create effective solutions. My communication skills come in to play when listening to the client's needs and explaining potential solutions in a clear and concise manner.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "The data analytics industry is continuously changing as new technology and products enter the market. How do you keep up-to-date on these changes, thereby contributing to the future success of Company ABC?", "answers": ["With the high level of competition in the Data Analytics industry, companies are continuously introducing new products and services to remain relevant. Company ABC would like to know that you will be proactive in educating yourself about the changes in the industry. Talk about resources you would use to remain informed to updates and changes in the Data Analytics industry. Also, communicate that you understand the importance of remaining current on the continuously evolving industry.", "\"Keeping abreast of the changes in the Data Analytics industry is important if a company wants to remain competitive. Companies need to know what technology is offered in the industry, so they don't lose their clients to the competition. I remain informed through various online resources such as industry blogs, journals, and community forums. Also, conferences and seminars are also informative sources to learn about changes in the industry, and I do my best to attend these regularly when budgets allow. Also, it is important to ensure that knowledge is shared across departments within the company. I have found holding sessions such as 'Lunch and Learns' help with the internal knowledge sharing.\"", "\"Keeping informed of the technological advances of the Data Analytics industry pushes companies to remain innovative themselves. I believe companies remain competitive by improving on the ideas of others. I remain informed through continuous communication with my network. Whether through email, online communities or social media, including LinkedIn and Twitter, I read articles from industry journals and information shared by my network. I believe it is important to be a part of an active network of professionals from the Data Analytics industry. Also, when my schedule allows, I attend networking events where I continually meet new Data Analytics industry professionals.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Describe your experience working with clients on the vendor side. If you only have client-side experience, describe how your skills can add value to Company ABC's client relationships.", "answers": ["Experience in maintaining strong client relationships is a valuable attribute when applying for a job at Company ABC. However, if you do not have any vendor-side expertise, you may have had similar experiences meeting the needs of internal clients. Although different, there are many similarities you can draw upon with regards to client relationship skills. Emphasize how you meet the requirements of clients (internal or external) and how you may have juggled several client projects at once. Touch on specific examples where you may have gone above and beyond to meet a client's needs.", "\"I have had experience working on the vendor side - interacting directly with clients and maintaining strong long-term relationships with them.  My work with a variety of clients has allowed me to strengthen and develop my organizational and prioritization skills as  I managed a variety of projects simultaneously. Also, I found that my ability to manage client expectations has been an invaluable skill that would be put to good use when working at Company ABC.\"", "\"My experience meeting the needs of internal clients will serve me well as a team member at Company ABC. Meeting the needs of a variety of internal clients strengthened many skills including communication and problem-solving. Understanding resource limitations within my company, I had to use my creative problem-solving skills to meet internal clients' needs. To do so, I had to be able to listen to client needs carefully and communicate solutions thoroughly. I believe teamwork skills are also vital as I worked together with my internal clients to complete projects.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Employees at Company ABC must work effectively in a team environment to ensure successful client solutions. What skills have you developed that will contribute to meaningful collaborations?", "answers": ["The hiring manager at Company ABC wants to be assured you understand what it takes to be an active and productive team member. Actively contributing to a team environment is critical when trying to find the best solutions for its clients. Explain what skills you bring to the table and how you can be a valuable team member at Company ABC.", "\"Over the years, I have found that communication skills are one of the most important skills to have when working on a team. I believe, just as important as expressing my views, is listening to others. My experiences have given me opportunities to draw thoughts and viewpoints out of others, thereby creating productive and valuable collaborations. I am confident I will be able to contribute to and lead meaningful collaborations to meet Company ABC's clients needs.\"", "\"Over the years, my experiences have allowed me to develop and strengthen my organization and leadership skills. I have found that if a team is to remain productive, it needs to stay on track and dedicated to the task or project on hand. Many times I have seen teams squander away valuable time and end meetings farther behind than they had hoped to be. As a team member at Company ABC, I will contribute my organizational and leadership skills to ensure productive meetings and progress that gets us closer to successful analytical solutions for Company ABC's clients. \""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Company ABC strives to remain at the forefront of innovation in this competitive industry. Describe a situation where you took the initiative to improve an existing process or develop a new one.", "answers": ["By asking this question, interviewers are looking for two things - initiative and creativity. First, they want to see that you identified a problem and took the bold step to search for a solution. They also would like to see your creativity displayed through the solution you present. The qualities in these types of situations display your dedication to the client and the company overall.", "\"Meeting client needs has always been a priority for me in all my previous positions. Each client's needs are unique and sometimes cannot be fully met with the products my company may offer at that time. With one particular client, I took the initiative to investigate a tailored solution for its unique analytical needs. This project took some creativity on my part as I managed the limited resources we had to come up with a solution. In the end, I was thrilled that we were able to devise a solution that met the needs of our client. I believe it is this level of service that helps companies remain competitive in this industry.\"", "\"In my past positions, any learnings from client projects were not shared across the company. Over time, I realized how valuable it would be to share these learnings to develop new products and services and ultimately better serve our clients. I initiated and developed a monthly sharing session that allowed client groups across our company share learnings from current or past client projects. Using these learnings, we were able to develop or improve our products and services. Sharing our learnings also sparked creative conversations that led us to investigate and make plans to develop new technologies for our clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "What do you think is the best way to communicate Company ABC's strengths and ultimately be considered by decision-makers looking for our services?", "answers": ["Your answer to this question will show your understanding of the Data Analytics industry overall. Be sure to mention who you believe to be the industry influencers and where decision makers go to get their information. Also, suggest any reputable social media channels you would use to help Company ABC communicate its products and services.", "\"I believe it is important to communicate to potential clients based on the industry in which they compete. It would be beneficial to target those industries in which Company ABC currently has clients. For example, if Company ABC's current client competes in the auto industry, communicate to potential clients in auto industry publications or target decision makers through sponsorships at industry events such as conferences. Company ABC will be able to prove their experience in the specific industry and also target these industry decision makers well. Potential clients will see that Company ABC already understands the specific issues their industry faces and the learning curve will not be steep.\"", "\"White papers are a great way to display Company ABC's knowledge and expertise to decision makers in the industry. These key decision makers usually make sure they are remaining current with all the new technology and research in the Data Analytics industry. Because you can request email addresses or contact information, white papers can build Company ABC's reputation while opening up communication lines with potential clients. White papers can be advertised to the target market on channels such as LinkedIn or industry publications.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Describe a time when you successfully collaborated with a client to help meet their business needs.", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to ensure you understand that teamwork can be very different when working with clients versus co-workers. Sometimes clients may not be interested in working as a team - they would like the company just to accomplish what they request. As you answer this question, convey that you understand teamwork is key to successful client projects and relationships. Be sure to identify the skills you utilized during your successful client collaboration.", "\"Through my various client experiences, I understand that teamwork with clients can sometimes be challenging, particularly if a client may not have a 'team' mindset. With one particular client, it was a challenge to convince her to invest time in collaboration. However, once I presented my case on the success she could achieve if we took the time to work together, I convinced her it would be worth it in the long run. Through our collaboration, we were able to use resources from both companies to build a solution that was cost-effective and impactful.  This data visualization tool met the client's needs within budget. Using my project management and communication skills, I was able to seamlessly coordinate resources from both locations to build a valuable solution in time and below budget.\"", "\"Through my experiences, I have found that collaboration can also play a role on the front end of projects. I worked with one particular client to better define his company's data analytics needs. After much investigation and deliberation, we decided that his current selection of our products was not the best option to meet his needs. Instead, we found a combination of another product and our consulting services better met his needs. My communication and sales skills allowed me to effectively gather the information I needed to convince him of this more effective solution.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "What do you believe will be the most difficult aspect of working at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The hiring manager wants to ensure you understand the potentially difficult aspects of the job and working in the Data Analytics industry. Your answer will reveal what you know about the position, the industry and the type of things you find challenging. With this type of question, end your response on a positive note by emphasizing your strengths or your drive to rise to the challenges presented to you.", "\"Due to the constant changes in the industry, I believe it will be a challenge to balance client work and additional training and learning opportunities. Although it is important to put much time and effort into delivering a high-quality solution to the client, I also believe it is important to invest time in educating ourselves on evolving technologies and trends in the Data Analytics industry. This training and education will help me better serve clients by offering cutting-edge solutions to their analytics needs. I believe my ability to organize and prioritize my time will help me overcome this challenge and ultimately equip me to  work with clients effectively.\"", "\"With a high level of competition and many players in this industry, it will be a challenge to innovate continuously. The challenge begins with remaining well informed of the competition and their products and services. Then we will have to take this knowledge and create innovative products for the clients. I believe everyone in the company should be responsible for learning about the competition and developing innovative ideas. I make it priorities to remain informed about changes in the industry and brainstorm ways to offer improved and unique products and services to clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Of the qualifications listed in our job posting, which ones do you feel you are most important for this position?", "answers": ["When posting open positions, hiring managers have an idea of which skills and qualifications are most important to have. This question will show whether you, as an applicant, perceive those same skills to be important. It will be an indication of how well you understand the requirements and necessary skills for the job. When communicating the qualifications you find most important, talk about how your education and experiences meet them. However, do not select a particular requirement or skill solely because it is a strength for you. If you feel a specific qualification or skill you find important is not a strength for you, mention how you would develop this area if hired.", "\"I believe client management and technical skills are two of the more important qualifications when considering a candidate for this position. Developing and maintaining client relationships is a high priority in companies in this industry. I have decades of experience working with clients to build successful analytics solutions. Also, having some level of technical experience will help me more thoroughly understand Company ABC's products, and subsequently better communicate the product attributes to current and potential clients. With each of my prior positions, I have gained more technical knowledge that has helped me with my client relationships.\"", "\"Project management skills and Data Analytics industry experience are the two qualifications I consider to be most important of those listed. Working efficiently and successfully across multiple client projects will require an advanced level of project management skills. Most of my work experience includes successfully working with multiple clients simultaneously which requires a high level of organization and prioritization skills.  Also, Data Analytics industry experience is valuable in understanding key trends and possible obstacles clients face when dealing with their analytics needs. Although my experience in this industry is limited, I have taken steps to educate myself through online courses and journal articles. I know having this knowledge will help me better serve Company ABC's clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Knowledge of client industries is crucial to identifying their needs. How will your various industry experiences help you meet our clients' needs?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like a better understanding of the industries you have been exposed to through your past work experiences. Research the industries in which Company ABC's clients compete, and in your response, highlight those in which you have experience. If you do not have experience in the specific industries, try to find similarities between Company ABC's client industries and your industry experiences. Speak to how your knowledge and skills in these industries would help you better serve Company ABC's clients.", "\"Based on my research, I learned that Company ABC has several clients in the financial services industry. I have worked for a few companies in this industry within different departments. Through these positions, I have been able to learn the data analytics needs of financial service companies from the perspective of different departments. Although I understand that clients competing in the same industry may have different analytics needs, I believe my experience gives me valuable knowledge that will help me serve Company ABC's clients more effectively. Also, I would hope that my knowledge and experience will quickly build credibility and trust with the clients.\"", "\"Although I do not have direct experience with Company ABC's client industries, I believe my experience in other industries would still be valuable while servicing your clients. As an example, my technical experience working in the Data Analytics group for a company in the Retail Clothing industry would be of value when working with Company ABC's clients in the Quick Service Restaurant industry. Companies in both industries work with Point of Sale data that present unique challenges from a data mining and overall analytics perspective. My experiences working through these challenges would be helpful in building relationships with Company ABC's Retail Clothing industry clients.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Outline for me your experience in risk management. Have you ever been exposed to an extreme data catastrophe?", "answers": ["In the data analytics industry, you can experience big wins, and you can experience significant data errors and issues. These can happen in the insurance industry or with any organization related to global risk management. If you have had experience working with a client or employer through a significant data crisis, outline the situation for the interviewer.", "\"My experience in risk management is primarily in the project catastrophe management space. I have a Degree in Project Management with a minor in risk assessment. I have helped a multitude of clients through situations of uncertainty, minimize threats, while maximizing opportunities. This experience is primarily in the insurance space with some environmental clients as well.\"", "\"I am a recent graduate with a Certificate in Professional Management specializing in Risk Management. My education will be best suited for data security breaches and causation. In the case of an extreme data catastrophe, I am prepared to assist my leader with creating a plan of action.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "How does data drive a business' success?", "answers": ["Data-driven decision making is becoming a more significant topic every year. Companies can leverage data analytics to determine: \n\n- Productivity \n- Competitive analysis\n- How, when, and where products are used\n- Customer demographics\n- Pattern analysis \n- Business growth \n\nTalk to the interviewer about the ways that you feel companies can best use data to drive the success of their business.", "\"When I take a hard look at the many uses of data, I see that data can be collected in a plethora of ways to determine the success of a new product launch, competitive analysis, or patterns that occur, which may not be seen by the human eye. In my career, I have the most experience using data to help drive employee productivity and onboarding solutions which can save a company thousands of dollars.\"", "\"Data can drive every aspect of a business' success if approached and utilized correctly. In my experience, I have seen that companies underutilize what a full data analysis approach can do for them. Analytics programs should be set up for marketing, sales, employee productivity, product efficiency, competitive analysis and more.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Outline for me your process when beginning a new project.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see if your process aligns well with the organization process at Company ABC. The other purpose of this question is to know if you have sound problem solving and organization skills. Discuss how you approach a new project, ensuring that you are successful from the start.", "\"When I first take on a project, I assess who I need on the case, and align my human resources and talent. Next, I schedule a client or department meeting to ensure that we set reasonable expectations. There, we create a timeline. Then, I create a data model using the data that we currently have, along with new measurements that may be required.\"", "\"I like to take a look at the project as a whole, along with a deep dive with the client or any stakeholders. Next, I will assemble my team and hire contractors as needed. A well established and reasonable timeline is created next. In my current role, I organize and manage all of this within Slack to ensure everything is in one place, for ease of reference and collaboration.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "Company ABC is learning focused. If you could take additional training in any job-related area, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Company ABC is expressing interest in educating you, and helping you to grow in your career knowledge and trajectory. Think of the education that would be required for you to take a step or two up in your career. You can also think of the training that the person has, to whom you would be reporting. Keep your answer to the point, ensuring that you show excitement for continued education and professional development.", "\"I have a keen interest in expanding my knowledge when it comes to advanced topics in pattern recognition. I realize that this coursework is a requirement for the roles above this opportunity so, to grow in my career, that is where I would like to begin.\"", "\"I appreciate that Company ABC offers continued education opportunities. To compliment my current education, and where I would like to grow in your organization, I would choose to take advanced coursework in information visualization. That topic is one of great interest to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "In your opinion, what is the most exciting collaboration between data analysis and artificial intelligence in the past year?", "answers": ["If you are up to date on the trends and happenings between data analysis and AI, you should have no problem answering this question. Discuss an exciting collaboration, project, or product release that you have heard of recently. Because this is an open-ended question, be careful not to ramble on.", "\"I have taken a keen interest in how artificial intelligence and machine learning algorithms have been working together to optimize business workflows. The result appears to be better strategies for enterprises surrounding people management, effective operations, as well as culture and engagement.\"", "\"I recently read an article in Forbes on the top machine learning programs to watch. I was especially intrigued with a company called DataVisor which uses machine learning to uncover financial data issues, helping to protect against bank fraud, and other financial based criminal activity.\""]}, {"topic": "Data+Analytics", "question": "The clientele at Company ABC spans many sectors. With which industries have you collaborated?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know the industries in which you bring the most experience. Perhaps you have worked in data analysis for marketing, sales, human resources, hospitality, health and medical, environmental, or insurance. Discuss with the interviewer the industries your past clients span. If you can, without breaking any non-disclosure agreements, talk about the most significant clients you have collaborated with.", "\"Through my research on Company ABC I see that your clients include A, B, and C. I have worked with similar organizations in the past such as X, Y, and Z. I am confident that my knowledge and exposure to these industries will translate very well to this particular position.\"", "\"The bulk of my experience is within the medical industry. I see that Company ABC has a few clients in the bioscience and pharma sectors. I would love to learn more about the clients on your medical and healthcare roster, their needs, and how my specific expertise can help.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Have you progressed in your career as you have expected?", "answers": ["Career progression can be a touchy subject, especially if you feel that your career hasn't progressed as well as you would have liked. Talk to the interviewer about your career progression and what you would like to see in the future.", "\"Overall, my career has progressed a touch slower than I would have liked. I have held a couple of positions that didn't offer the growth and learning that I was expecting; however, I have bounced back nicely. I feel that this particular position would take my career exactly where it should be.\"", "\"I have been very intentional with my career moves and progression and am happy with the path that my career has taken me.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What type of manager brings out the best in you?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you are self-aware and understand the type of manager or employer that brings out the best in you. Some individuals prefer a close working relationship with a lot of accountability while others prefer space and autonomy. If you are unsure of the management style of the interviewing company, try to leave your answer as open as possible. You can certainly ask the interviewer to describe their management style.", "\"I have worked with a wide range of personalities and management styles with great success. If I could express a preference, I feel that I am best in an independent and autonomous environment. Can you describe the management style here?\"", "Here are some management styles: \n\n- Directive Autocrat\n- Permissive Autocrat\n- Consultative Style\n- Persuasive Style \n- Inclusive \n- Democratic Style \n- MBWA (Management By Walking Around)\n- Laissez-faire\n- Mentorship Style"]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Do you always double check or proofread your work?", "answers": ["Double checking and proofreading are critical parts of a job well done. Assure the interviewer that you are diligent when it comes to submitting good, clean, work.", "\"Spelling and grammatical errors are a pet peeve of mine. I will triple check my work if there is time! I feel that it is essential to submit error-free work.\"", "\"Yes, absolutely I do! Accuracy is incredibly important in the IT industry and I would never compromise quality  in order to save time.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What questions do you have for me about Company ABC?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to have questions ready for the interviewer. Review the company website and other online resources to ensure the questions you are asking are not mundane, or redundant. The last thing an interviewer wants to hear is a list of items you could have found the answers to from merely watching a video on their company site! \n\nHere are some sample questions: \n\n- When would you like to have this position filled? \n- How long has this role been vacant? \n- Is this a replacement search or a newly created role? \n- What is your favorite part about working here? \n- What is the company's primary goal for this position in the next 12 months? \n- Is there anything from my background and experience that I can clarify for you? \n- What do you see as the most significant change in this industry over the past three years? \n- Is there any reason why you would not hire me?", "\"Thank you for asking - I do have a few questions. What is top of mind when it comes to filling this role? Also, what types of career growth opportunities would follow this position? And lastly, do you have internal candidates who are also interviewing for this position?\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Company ABC seeks to hire those with above average communication skills. Describe your communication style to me.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that your communication style will fit in with the culture they have worked on creating at Company ABC. When clients seek the help of Company ABC, they do so with certain expectations. Convince the interviewer that your communication style will meet those expectations. It's best to give a few unique keywords when discussing your communication style. Also be sure to compliment Company ABC on their communication efforts.", "\"I have been a client of Company ABC in the past and can truly say that positive communication with your clients is what makes you the most popular choice in the area. I am confident that my communication skills will work well here because my focus always remains on simple solutions, easy to understand language, and a friendly tone.\"", "Here are some additional words to describe your communication style: \n\n- Energetic\n- Lively\n- Articulate \n- Eloquent\n- Informal\n- Formal\n- Succinct"]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Would you be willing to work over 40 hours a week?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the interviewer's expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you. \n\nKeep in mind that, in most states, an employer cannot demand that an employee work more than 44 hours per week.", "\"I am available for full-time work which is preferably 8-5 Monday to Friday. I am happy to be a team player and work some overtime, as required. Will these hours meet your expectations?\"", "\"If overtime is required in this role, I am happy to accommodate whenever I can. My only restriction is that I cannot work Wednesday nights as I have an evening course those days.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those with a passion for the IT industry. How do you stay up to date on industry changes and current events?", "answers": ["Being up to date on industry terms, trends, and news is critical in a fast-moving industry such as IT and IT services. The interviewer would like to know that you have a genuine interest in their industry. Speak briefly about the ways you stay up to date on the industry changes and current events by referring to specific sources. You can also ask the interviewer about their favorite resources.", "\"This industry is ever-changing, and I have a true and keen interest in keeping up-to-date on those changes. I regularly read a couple of great online publications including PC Mag and Wired. Do you have any recommendations for great resources?\"", "\"My current employer sends a daily email with the company and industry updates. This update is beneficial and, I am sure to read it thoroughly every day. I also have Google alerts set up so that I am up to date on new trends and happenings in the industry.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What are your thoughts on web-based, click to chat support solutions?", "answers": ["Whenever you are asked your opinion on an industry-related topic, you should try to be honest but positive at the same time. Whether you like web-based, click to chat support solutions or not, you should be focusing your answer on why you think they may be helpful. If Company ABC offers a service like this you should also ask them an insightful question about that service.", "\"I have heard mixed reviews from customers on this type of service. In my opinion, any service that allows a client quick access to answers is a positive thing. Have you noticed a shift in your client relationships since implementing this type of solution?\"", "\"Personally, I like the idea of click to chat support solutions so long as they don't become 'spammy.' The placement of the pop-up box should be convenient, and they should be personalized, so they do not appear to be a templated after-thought to the end-user.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Tell me something about yourself that I wouldn't know from reading your resume.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you apart from what is on your resume. You are indeed not obligated to discuss personal matters such as your kids, or relationship status, for instance. Stick with a couple of fun facts to show the interviewer that you are a real person, too. Your answer should be unique so that you are a memorable candidate!  \n\nFocus on unique non-work related skills or hobbies.  For example, you might share that you enjoy beat-boxing or making origami swans. Be prepared for the interviewer to stop you and ask you to perform your skill on the spot when it's possible! (This will make you unforgettable!)", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit.\"", "\"I am bilingual in Spanish and have some proficiency in French and Italian, too. I also am a huge Harry Potter fan and could pretty much quote each book to you.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "We are asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question presents an opportunity to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in the IT industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career, such as telecommunications and securities. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Would you say you are a better verbal or written communicator?", "answers": ["In which manner do you prefer to communicate - written or verbal? Discuss your preference with the interviewer and support your answer.", "\"I prefer verbal communication because I feel that with written communication, a lot can be misread due to lack of tone, fluctuation, expression and body language. I will always choose a face to face conversation whenever possible.\"", "\"I like to leverage both methods of communications when dealing in business. Sometimes, situations call for verbal communications and other times, written.  As a rule of thumb, I tend to practice verbal communications, with written follow up.  Utilizing multiple methods creates repetition and therefore, change.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we deal with sensitive and confidential client information. Are you willing to complete a full background check?", "answers": ["Most companies in the IT and IT Services industry need to be very cautious about who they hire. There is a chance that much of the information you are going to access could be confidential and harmful if put into the wrong hands. Assure the interviewer that you are most willing to comply with any form of background check they require.", "\"I am happy to comply with any background check required. My record is clean, and I have a strong credit history. I do not participate in drug use, either. You can be assured that if you hire me for this role with Company ABC, I will maintain a clean record.\"", "\"Yes, I can certainly complete a full background check. I should disclose to you ahead of time that I have a mark on my record from about eight years ago, for a DUI. I am still able to travel, and no longer have restrictions on my drivers' license.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "How do you make tough decisions knowing they will affect your entire team?", "answers": ["It can be difficult to make challenging decisions when you know that your entire team will be affected. Your ability to be decisive and diplomatic will make all the difference! \n\nIf you take a more team-oriented approach, share how you collaborate with the group by inviting everyone to discuss their opinions and come to a census. If you prefer to take charge of these situations, share how you step up to a decision while still taking everyone's needs and feelings into consideration.", "\"Leaders are truly set apart by their ability to make tough decisions respectfully and diplomatically. Last year we had to lay off 25% of our sales team. I knew that there would be feelings hurt and it was challenging to do. I got through it by reminding myself that I am the leader for a reason. I needed to trust my judgment but still be able to justify my decisions in the end. Many times when tough choices are in front of me, I will back up my gut feeling with data analysis. If the data supports my intuition, I know what the answer or decision needs to be.\"", "\"I believe that when you are working with a team, it is important to bring any questions or situations to the team before making a decision. Everyone should have input; however, the leader needs to be able to pull the trigger on all decisions in the end.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "How do you evaluate success among your team members?", "answers": ["When you are leading a team, it is imperative to be aware of the level of success that each team member is experiencing. One underperforming team player can drag down the entire group. Talk to the interviewer about how you can stay aware of each team members' success.", "\"I have a very in-depth and successful system for evaluating success among my team members. I check in twice per week with each member of my team. On Mondays - to set our goals together. Then, on Fridays, to discuss any successes and challenges. I have them self-evaluate, and then we create a plan for success for the upcoming week. I evaluate their success based on their follow through and willingness to work hard to reach their goals.\"", "\"I typically have KPI (key performance indicators) in place to measure the success of each of the members of the team.  I also manage our overall success in working together. For example, are we hitting on key initiatives within the department, developing each other for succession planning and having fun along the way!\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we have detailed procedures in place for client technical support. What would you do if those procedures did not appear to be working?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to understand how you handle high-pressure situations and unexpected difficulties in the workplace. Discuss the steps you would take if this situation happened to you.", "\"It is important to always have procedures in place, but I understand that sometimes those procedures do not encompass all client needs. If I came across a situation like this, I would rely on my knowledge and experience to troubleshoot and find a solution. If I did not have the answer, I would then ask for help from my supervisor or a colleague. It is important to stay calm in situations like these, so the client remains confident in our capabilities. I would never tell a client that I didn't have an answer. 'I will find out' is always the best answer.\"", "\"I do not mind going slightly off script if needed. There are sometimes extenuating circumstances where the process does not necessarily work. I will gain permission from my employer if it's a bigger concern than usual since I still want to follow the procedure as much as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "We put a great deal of pride in our customer service at Company ABC. How will you contribute to our high customer service standards?", "answers": ["Before your interview, it's a great idea to spend time researching Company ABC reviews, their online presence, and their website. Take note of recurring keywords when it comes to their customer service standards. What are their clients saying? Speak confidently about how you plan to uphold their strong customer service standards if hired.", "\"Your customers have a strong voice, and I noticed a consistent theme in your online reviews and presence. The theme was that you offer friendly, fast, and easy to understand service. I plan to contribute to this by learning my role quickly and continuing to be an approachable and helpful point of contact for the customers who need us.\"", "\"I will contribute to your high customer service standards by offering a listening ear and ensuring that I fully understand your products and services. The more I know, the more I will be able to offer your client base.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Our industry is a competitive one. Why do you specifically want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you have a keen interest in working for Company ABC. You should enter the interview prepared to discuss why they stand out as the top employment option, among their competitors. Talk about what you feel Company ABC is doing right and how their values and opportunities align with your career goals and employment needs.", "\"I understand that Company ABC has some strong competitors but when I was researching new employment opportunities, your company always seemed to have the most positive message. I also know a couple of people who have worked with Company ABC and they had only great things to say about your compensation, culture, and growth opportunities.\"", "\"I feel that Company ABC would nurture my desire for growth and prepare me with the appropriate training to support that growth.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Walk me through your post-secondary education and how it will help you in your career with Company ABC.", "answers": ["The interviewer will likely have an idea of your education background from your resume. What they are asking is for you to take a few minutes to bring the experience to life for them! You can talk about your major, or any special academic recognition you may have received. Discuss the strengths gained during your post-secondary training and how those skills will be used in your new position with Company ABC.", "\"I completed my Bachelor of Applied Technology from Carnegie Mellon University in 2004. During that time I specialized in Data Management and Analysis. I graduated with a 3.67 GPA, one of the top in my class. One of the biggest take-away's from my post-secondary experience was learning how to manage my time while working on multiple projects successfully. I perfected my multi-tasking skills and look forward to bringing those to work for Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I do not have formal post-secondary education, I have taken some courses in customer support, upselling, and a variety of software programs. I look forward to gaining even more knowledge in this role with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we believe in continued education of our employees. If you could take a course or workshop on any topic, what would you choose?", "answers": ["Working for a company which emphasizes the importance of continued education can be an enriching opportunity. Be prepared to talk to the interviewer about your interest in growing your knowledge base. You may want to push your existing knowledge into the expert range, or perhaps there is a current hot topic on which you would like to learn. Whatever your answer may be, ensure that you express to the interviewer your appreciation for continued education opportunities.", "\"I love that Company ABC emphasizes continued education. This offering is one of the qualities I was looking for, in my next opportunity. If I could take a course or workshop on any topic I would choose to focus on IT Management. My goal is to grow into a management level position, and that would be a great stepping stone to get there.\"", "\"That is very exciting news to hear. I value continued education as well. If I could continue my education in any area, I would do a deeper dive into IT Security and IT Security Management.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Tell me about your experience in the field of IT services.", "answers": ["It is critical that you study the job description before your interview. When the interviewer asks this question be sure to highlight the related experience that you bring.", "\"I bring all of the experience that you are looking for in filling this position. In addition to being an expert user in SAP, I also bring five years' experience in desk side support and as a bilingual IT support agent.\"", "\"I have eight years of industry experience with Company ABC and XYZ. Both experiences taught me a great deal about IT, and I am excited to continue my career in this industry with your organization.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What part of this career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (IE: a bus driver should not find driving to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"The part of my career that brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on my teams part. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that my clients are assisted properly.\"", "\"I probably bring myself the most stress because of my drive and desire to be/do the best I can be.  I manage this by focusing my energy on productive activities that are good for my career.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you had to be extra diligent in order to meet a deadline.", "answers": ["Are you determined to complete your tasks on time or do you frequently miss deadlines? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to act diligently on the job.", "\"Last month I had a client who made a lot of additional and last minute changes to our project. Despite the changes, our deadline remained the same. Our project lead was becoming increasingly stressed that we would not meet our deadline so I agreed to stay late three nights that week to ensure that all expectations were met.\"", "\"I am always diligent when it comes to deadlines.  However, once I remember having an abnormally large order from a regular client once.  I was a little stressed about making sure it was perfect, but I was confident, and we met our deadline with no issue.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What characteristics or events have contributed towards your success as a leader?", "answers": ["Why do you think that you are a successful leader? Talk to the interviewer about the variety of things that you believe have led you to your success.", "\"There is a multitude of factors that have helped me to become a strong leader. First and foremost; I had an outstanding mentor from a young age. Secondly, I have studied leadership at great length. My personality has also contributed to my success as I am a natural coach, teacher, and leader.\"", "Here are some other factors that make a successful leader:\n\n- Having a good example, and replicating that example \n- Working on continual development, both professionally and personally \n- Being diligent when it comes to fully understanding your business\n- The ability to make solid decisions, in a timely manner\n- The ability to delegate when you know you aren't the best person for the task\n- Maintaining a positive attitude even when times are tough \n- Admitting when you are wrong, and holding yourself accountable\n- Keeping your team in the loop on current and upcoming changes"]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one-sided hunt. You must also feel as though this is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer what your ideal employer looks like. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "Here are some other ways you could describe a great employer. A great employer will: \n\n- Pause to have fun now and then but also know when to be serious\n- Treat everyone fairly, and equally\n- Offer rewards for great work\n- Offer a continually challenging environment \n- Offer flexibility and understands that personal situations come up from time to time\n- Encourage a collaborative workplace"]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Companies will have confidentiality agreements for a variety of reasons. These could be to protect their trade secrets or to ensure that you do not bring clients over on the occasion that you leave their company. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements.", "\"I never have, to my knowledge, broken a confidentiality agreement. Despite my reasons for leaving a position, I would never choose to hurt a previous employer in any way.\"", "\"I understand the importance of confidentiality agreements and would never breach a sensitive agreement like that.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "When have you had to change a major component of your project due to new information being presented?", "answers": ["Being able to swivel the focus of your project is a necessary skill for your success in most careers. Talk to the interviewer about a time when a significant change occurred on a project. How did you handle the implementation of the new information?", "\"I had a large project last month that was nearly complete when the client called to say that the dimensions provided were incorrect. Because of this, our team had to re-do the entire proposal. It took us an additional four days of work but, in the end, the client was delighted with our work, and it resulted in new opportunities with them.\"", "\"Last year we saw new federal regulations come through which affected 80% of our ongoing projects. We had to adjust our plans quickly; however, we were able to deliver a timely product that met federal regulations.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "When you suffer a setback, how does that emotionally affect you and your work?", "answers": ["Everyone handles the stress and disappointment of setbacks differently. Discuss with the interviewer how you typically cope with delays in the workplace.", "\"Experiencing a setback is always disappointing, and can be a bit disheartening, but I understand that it happens from time to time. If I experience a major setback, I will take a few moments to debrief with my manager and discuss what I could have done differently. Then, I move on!\"", "\"Setbacks happen for a reason, and they do not affect me emotionally in the least. I am a very pragmatic thinker and stay focused despite the challenges that come my way.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "How would your most recent manager describe you?", "answers": ["When you answer this question, draw from your last performance review and a piece of feedback you have received from your most recent boss or coworkers. You do not want to guess what your manager thinks of you. Solidify your answer by referring to the strong employment references you are able to provide.", "\"In my recent performance reviews and discussions, my manager describes me as a hard worker, motivated and consistent employee. I always strive to exceed expectations when I can. My current manager is happy to speak on my behalf as a positive reference as well.\"", "\"My last manager and I had a close relationship. She appreciated all of my efforts when it came to working overtime and taking my work home when required. I believe she would describe me as unique, reliable and energetic.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "When have you worked amongst a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"I would say that pretty much every company I have worked for has valued diversity.  Working with people from all walks of life help shed different perspectives and identify potential problems faster.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you, at this time in your career?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical 'I am looking for growth' answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"I have been passively seeking a new position for quite some time and haven't jumped on anything yet because I want to make sure it's the right fit. I feel that this job is right for me, at this point in my career, because it offers an opportunity for me to utilize my recent education in IT while giving me an opportunity to advance in my management skills.\"", "\"This job is right for me at this time in my career because I am prepared and ready to take on a management position. I feel that your company would nurture my desire for growth and prepare me with the appropriate training.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "What decisions did you routinely make in your last position?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of decisions you are accustomed to making in the workplace. The way you answer this questions will give them a good idea of your level of experience, seniority, and ability to handle the decision-making requirements in this possible position. \n\nIf the job you are interviewing for requires you to be decisive and quick on your feet, you will need to be able to provide examples of how you have done these things in the past. If you worked in tech support, you faced problems that you needed to find solutions for on a regular basis. If you worked as a sales rep, you might have required to know how to negotiate and make decisions on prices and benefits you can give your customers. \n\nYou may have faced decisions that became so routine you didn't think twice! Refer to these types of decisions and be sure to highlight how these types of decisions have prepared you for a role like this one.", "\"In my previous position I was quite often required to make decisions on staff scheduling as well as hiring and terminating. I feel that role prepared me quite well for a position like this one. I have well-honed decision-making skills and my intuition, when it comes to hiring, has been elevated.\"", "\"I was responsible for planning the content calendar: emails, blog post topics, and timing, social media posts, in addition to actually executing the plans. That means everything from creating web copy, to choosing images, and the like. Also, I collaborate with management to decide what promotions and sales we will be running, and when.\""]}, {"topic": "IT+Services", "question": "If you were hired today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would start with analyzing all quantifiable data from the last month, quarter, and year to identify any bottlenecks or shortfalls and set a plan to correct them.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "The product standards at Company ABC are highly regulated. Do you consider yourself meticulous and detail-oriented?", "answers": ["Product standards should be high! Be sure to address with the interviewer how important the small details are to you. The interviewer would like to see that you have a keen interest in the details. Give an example of a time when your attention to detail saved the company from an expensive error or a safety issue.", "\"After researching Company ABC I could see that your organization has a keen eye for the details. I, too, am a detail-oriented person. Two months ago, during our quarterly audit, I noticed a couple of discrepancies that ended up saving my company $45,000. My supervisor was very thankful for my keen eye and ended up making me the inventory lead for future audits.\"", "\"Yes, at this point in my career, I do consider myself detail-oriented. My attention to detail is a point that I have been working on a lot this past year. I am meticulous but, in the past, have pushed my documentation back a little bit. It's something I am conscious of and continually working on.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Do you have any formal education or training in the semiconductor field? How does that training relate to what we do at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how your post-secondary education and training relates to a career with Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that you have a keen interest in the semiconductor industry by mentioning any formal, or informal, training you have completed. You can also include any self-training as well! Give an answer that will show off your drive to learn more about this industry.", "\"Although I do not have formal post-secondary training in the semiconductor industry, I do bring ten years' experience in the field, with hands-on training. Is there any particular formal training that you would like me to take before starting with Company ABC?\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What skills did you learn in your last position that will help you in this new role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Before answering this question, you need to know which fundamental skills are required in this role. Review the job description, compare it to your most recent job, and give examples that demonstrate your competency in these skills. \n\nFor instance, if Company ABC is looking for someone with experience in a particular technology, talk about how you learned the ins and outs of this technology in your past job. If the company is looking for someone with excellent customer service skills, give an example of how you learned to meet the needs of customers in your last role by listening and positively communicating with them.", "Here are some transferable skills that may apply to you:\n\n- Effective leadership \n- Presentations and public speaking \n- Specific software or technology\n- Research and data analysis"]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "If Company ABC offered you the position, when would you be available to start?", "answers": ["Make sure before an interview; you have a start date in mind for the new employer. Come prepared to answer this question affirmatively, whether you need to give two weeks to your previous position or can start right away.", "\"As a professional courtesy, I would like to give my current employer two weeks' notice. I could start anytime after that.\"", "\"I am currently unemployed; however, I have a long weekend trip planned from the 12th to the 15th. I would be thrilled to start the Tuesday after that.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "At Company ABC we like to hire those who are natural leaders. When have you taken on a leadership task in the workplace without being asked?", "answers": ["Most companies want to know that they are hiring someone who can grow with their company, show initiative, and be an excellent example to others. Talk to the interviewer about a time, big or small, when you took the initiative to go above your regular duties and set an example of leadership for your co-workers.", "\"Last month when our supervisor was out unexpectedly we had a couple of temporary employees not show up for their assignment. We were short-handed, and volumes were high. I decided to step up for the team, like a leader would do, and offered to work a double shift so that last-minute overtime was not expected of my team members. I enjoy setting an example of teamwork while maintaining a positive mindset.\"", "\"I will often take new hires under my wing, unasked. I believe that it helps with retention when new employees feel like others are interested in their success.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We try to hire people who want to stay with Company ABC long term. What are your long term career plans and how do we fit into your plans?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your longer-term career plans and how they fit into the career path being offered by Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that you are looking for a longer term fit.", "\"I am looking for a long-term career path which is one of the reasons I applied to work with Company ABC. I like that you have opportunities for advancement within your team and that you offer professional development coursework. If hired, I would seek to work my way into a leadership role with Company ABC.\"", "\"This position aligns nicely with my career goal of continued growth in the semiconductor industry.  The role is in my comfort zone, but a new enough approach that will intrigue me, and the company size is adequate to support growth. I would love to, in the longer term, find myself working in a leadership position at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Tell me about a project you worked on where a conventional approach was not suitable.", "answers": ["How have you implemented creativity in the workplace when a conventional approach was not suitable? Display for the hiring manager how you can think outside of the box when necessary.", "\"In 2009 our economy suffered, and a lot of businesses were struggling to keep their doors open. At that time, a conventional approach was to take out additional ads on the radio or TV. Social media was starting to become a major advertising outlet - and it was free. I launched a social media campaign that was very successful. We were able to generate new and repeat business while coming in under our advertising budget.\"", "\"I recently worked on a project that was ahead of its time and federal guidelines.  If you want to achieve something you never have before, you have to do something you have never done. We took an unconventional approach to federal research and licensing technology through the Office of Technology Transfer in a way never done before. It was a necessary step to achieve the bigger picture.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We value strong tenure at Company ABC. Why were you fired or let go from your last job?", "answers": ["Being terminated does not have to be an embarrassing or shameful thing. Be open and honest with the interviewer regarding your dismissal. Be sure to let the interviewer know that you can provide positive references despite a previous termination.", "\"I was terminated from my last position due to my inability to relocate to the new plant that my company was opening. It was unfortunate, but I am confident that I will find the right fit again shortly. Despite my termination, I can provide you with strong work references.\"", "\"I lost my position due to the company being acquired by a larger competitor. It was disappointing because I was hoping to stay with that company for a long time. With that said, everything happens for a reason, and I am excited for a fresh start with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Company ABC uses some well-known software programs. Which automation software solutions you are accustomed to using?", "answers": ["There are many automation software solution options. Some are for the masses, and other organizations may have proprietary software. \n\nWhen asked about your exposure to these types of programs it is important to remember that most of them function the same because the desired outcome is always similar. If you know one, you should be able to understand another more easily. \n\nAvoid focusing on what you don't know and focus on what you do. Assure the interviewer that you can learn their system quickly.", "\"You mention in your job posting that you are looking for someone with experience in Software ABC. I have worked with Software XYZ which is very similar. The functions are essentially the same, and since I am an expert level user in XYZ, I am confident that I will be a fast learner when it comes to ABC and your other internal programs.\"", "\"I am most accustomed to using Applied Materials automation software. Primarily, it's function is to coordinate process and people so that we can optimize our resources. I am a fast learner and am confident that I will learn your internal solutions very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "At Company ABC we want to hire those with at least a basic understanding of semiconductors. Why are some semiconductors made of silicon?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your basic industry knowledge. The better you understand a topic, the more clearly you should be able to answer a question like this. Keep your answer concise. 'I don't know' is never an acceptable answer. You should be transparent with the interviewer that you are unsure of the solution but offer any piece of knowledge that you may have. \n\nIf you know the answer: \"From my understanding, some semiconductors are made of silicon because the semiconductor can then be used at much higher temperatures; for electronics, for example.\"", "\"From my understanding, some semiconductors are made of silicon because the semiconductor can then be used at much higher temperatures; for electronics, for example.\"", "If you do not know the answer: \"I am not confident on why some semiconductors are made of silicon; however, I do believe that silicon is good for higher heat so perhaps that is why? I would love to learn more if you would give me the opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What are your strengths?", "answers": ["Which personal advantages make you excellent at your job? Strengths can be skills or qualities that help you overcome difficult circumstances or accomplish challenging tasks. \n\nIn a work context, your strengths will help you to complete your to-do list, understand client needs, and help you to apply what you have learned in your training. Talk to the interviewer about a couple of your strengths and why those will help you to be successful in this role.", "\"I think my strengths are in my perceptiveness and ability to be observant of the needs of others. These strengths are part of what makes me an excellent performer in a client facing role.\"", "Here is a list of strengths that you may have:\n\n- Strong enthusiasm in the workplace \n- Trustworthiness and honesty\n- Adaptability and versatility \n- Patience\n- Determination and diligence\n- Leadership and teamwork"]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"Honesty is always the best policy. Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message so managing this with each situation is critical to building honest and trustworthy relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "How have you had to adapt your work style to fit the team's objectives?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you are open to change and are adaptable. Think about the times when you have had to learn a new computer system, change your email organization approach, change how you update your calendar, re-worked your daily routine, or times when you have had to change your approach to meeting a goal. These are all great examples for this question! \n\nStart off by telling the interviewer your usual work style in this area, and share how you changed this work style to meet the team's objectives. Be sure to mention that you didn't mind the change, and you were happy to accommodate this change to help the team reach its goal.", "\"Typically, I like to begin my day by listening to voicemail, checking emails, and making a to-do list for the day. The goal of this particular team was to increase staff communication, so we decided to start each morning with a team huddle instead. This meant that I was unable to kick-off my day with my usual morning routine. I was happy to meet for the team huddles because I understood that they were helping us meet our goal of improving communication.\"", "\"My current team is more junior, and they require constant communication - more than I am naturally inclined to provide. For this reason, I have had to adapt my communication style to include more touch-points in the day. I have learned a lot from having a greener team, and appreciate the opportunity to expand my working style.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Explain Statistical Process Control (SPC) to me.", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your basic industry knowledge. The better you understand a topic, the more clearly you should be able to answer a question like this. Keep your answer concise. 'I don't know' is never an appropriate answer. You should be transparent with the interviewer that you are unsure of the solution but offer any piece of knowledge that you may have. \n\nIf you know the answer: \"From my understanding, SPC is an industry-wide standard for measuring and controlling the quality during the manufacturing process.\"", "\"From my understanding, SPC is an industry-wide standard for measuring and controlling the quality during the manufacturing process.\"", "If you do not know the answer: \"I am not confident on the exact purpose of SPC; however I believe it may be a way of controlling industry standards? I would love to learn more if you would give me the opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We want to ensure that Company ABC has the best inventory over our competitors. Have you ever made a suggestion on a product line or item?", "answers": ["An engaged employee will notice when changes are required. They make recommendations and suggestions they feel will benefit the organization. Have you ever taken the lead by making a recommendation to your employer? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you suggested the workplace.", "\"I made a recommendation last month that we try a new line of parts after one of our particular vendors shorted us on inventory. The vendor that I suggested was newer to the industry. With that said, their customer service was impressive. Their pricing was competitive as well. We gave them a shot, and it worked out well for us, resulting in cost savings, a better product, and happier customers.\"", "\"I consistently make well-researched and well-backed suggestions to my current employer. They have a great open door policy which I like to utilize as often as possible. If I can be a help when it comes to process and product suggestions, then I feel that I am helping my company to be more profitable as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We strive to be the best in our industry. What do you think Company ABC could improve on?", "answers": ["A great organization will always be open to improvement and innovation. The interviewer would like to know if you have suggestions for improvement; however, they are indeed not asking you to reinvent their wheel. \n\nThe worst thing you could do here is to speak negatively about the company without any constructive feedback or recommended solution. If you do have a suggestion, keep it light and be sure to end your remark with a positive comment.", "\"I think that you are doing an impressive job at Company ABC and I look forward to coming to work with you. If I could make any suggestion, I would suggest more updates on the company blog. I believe your vendors and distributors are interested in what Company ABC has to say and where you are taking the company in the future!\"", "\"I enjoy what you do at Company ABC, and how you do it. If anything, I would suggest a bit more advertising on more modern platforms such as social media and through collaborative endorsements.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What is the biggest difference between Intrinsic and Extrinsic semiconductors?", "answers": ["The interviewer is testing your basic industry knowledge. The better you understand a topic, the more clearly you should be able to answer a question like this. Keep your answer concise. \n\nIf you do not know the answer, it is essential that you make an educated guess. \"I don't know\" is never the right answer. You should be transparent with the interviewer that you are unsure of the solution but offer any piece of knowledge that you may have. \n\nIf you know the answer: \"From my understanding, Intrinsic semiconductors are made from very pure materials where Extrinsic semiconductors are made with trace impurities.\"", "\"I am not confident on the difference between Intrinsic and Extrinsic semiconductors. I have worked with Extrinsic semiconductors which I know contain some impurities so perhaps Intrinsic semiconductors are made with only pure materials? I would love to learn more if you would give me the opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Time management is the key to productivity at Company ABC. How do you manage your time?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of tools you use to stay on task and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about the ways you manage your projects and daily tasks.", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking.' This process means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day. Setting calendar alerts and personal deadlines for myself has also helped a lot.\"", "\"I manage my time best by using a select few programs dedicated to project and time management. My favorites are Freedcamp and Trello. Because I am technically savvy, I also utilize Google calendar every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Tell me about a time that you were asked to collaborate on a project with a colleague whom you did not necessarily see eye-to-eye with. How did you ensure that you got along well and met your deadline?", "answers": ["Getting along with different personalities is especially vital in the workplace. Explain that you can be flexible and hear someone out even if you don't agree with them. Showcase your ability to learn from others when you may not wholeheartedly agree with their perspective or approach.", "\"Recently we received a project from a client that required my department to collaborate with a rival department within marketing. It was up to me to ensure that everyone worked smoothly together. The other departments' manager and I decided to start with a team building night out, and that helped a lot. Once everyone was able to find common ground, we could focus on the task at hand.\"", "\"I had an issue with my manager a few years ago because we disagreed on the course of action to take on a project that was going sideways. The discussion started to heat up, so I quickly let her know that I thought it was best we think about our course of action overnight, and book a formal meeting to discuss the challenges. We scheduled a meeting for the following day and were able to resolve the issue. In the end, she told me she appreciated my conflict management skills, my professional awareness and personal maturity surrounding the situation.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Sometimes we come across unique problems at Company ABC. What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creative side. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible, I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What is your definition of hard work?", "answers": ["Hard work and dedication can be interpreted differently by everyone. To one person, another person's hard work could seem like slacking. Talk to the interviewer about how you interpret a hard day's work.", "\"For me, hard work means that I did what I could that day to exceed expectations. I come to work early and stay late if needed and I go over and above the requirements without hesitation.\"", "\"I know that I am working hard when I can be proud of my accomplishments at the end of each shift. Would I be proud to show my supervisor the work that I completed for the day? If the answer is 'yes,' then I know I gave my all that day.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We want to hire motivated leaders at Company ABC. What do you find to be the most difficult aspect of leading your current team?", "answers": ["The interviewer is trying to learn more about the challenges you currently face, as a leader. If hired, this information will help the company to know where you could use additional training, encouragement, or education.  \n\nEvery leader has an aspect that is challenging for them. Share your most challenging aspect of leadership but also highlight the steps that you take to alleviate or overcome that challenge. \n\nOne common challenge for leaders is the need to terminate an employee. Another problem could be continually motivating unengaged employees. A big challenge could also be sourcing and utilize the best hiring resources to shave down your time spent on reading resumes.", "\"One challenge that I face as a leader is to avoid frustration when employees show continued disinterest in our company's education opportunities. My current company has an amazing program available for continued education, yet only about 32% of our employees take advantage. To alleviate this frustration, I am starting a company-wide recognition program for all employees who explore this option with our company.\"", "\"I find the most difficult part of leading my current team is to maintain a positive mentality throughout the entire group. We have a couple of individuals who try to drag the team down when it comes to morale. It's always hard to combat that, but I do my best by reinforcing all positive behaviors.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "It is important to us that Company ABC maintains a healthy and collaborative work environment. What kind of people do you enjoy working with?", "answers": ["Culture fit is a critical factor when looking for a new position. Talk to the interviewer about the types of personalities that you best work with. Be sure to remain positive and avoid using this as an opportunity to speak poorly of previous colleagues.", "\"I best enjoy working with individuals who are driven, positive, energetic, and take accountability for their work. I do have the ability to work with a large variety of individuals; however, these are the ideal traits I would see in future colleagues.\"", "\"My favorite people to work with are individuals who are passionate about their trade and want to make a difference for their company on a daily basis. Those who take pride in their work always have my utmost respect.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "We are asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This question is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have five years' experience vs. eight years' experience I can do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my five years working in this industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What do you think you will like about this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you are looking forward to learning and growing in this new position. Talk about what excites you! Share how this position will challenge you and help you to grow. New opportunities are a chance for you to demonstrate your transferable skills.", "\"I am looking forward to gaining more experience in the semiconductor industry, and I look forward to applying my engineering education in a more structured corporate environment. I believe that Company ABC is an industry leader where I can successfully grow my career.\"", "\"You deliver a product/service that makes a difference in the lives of your clients.  (Insert organization mission statement or values).  This is that type of organization I admire and want to be a part of.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you had to be extra diligent in order to meet a deadline.", "answers": ["Are you determined to complete your tasks on time or do you frequently miss deadlines? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to act diligently on the job.", "\"Last month I had a client who made a lot of additional and last minute changes to our project. Despite the changes, our deadline remained the same. Our project lead was becoming increasingly stressed that we would not meet our deadline so I agreed to stay late three nights that week to ensure that all expectations were met.\"", "\"I am always diligent when it comes to deadlines.  However, once I remember having an abnormally large order from a regular client once.  I was a little stressed about making sure it was perfect, but I was confident, and we met our deadline with no issue.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "When have you used an inventive method to stretch company resources beyond the normal level?", "answers": ["If you have an expense account or resource allowance, it is very respectful to the company to be as thoughtful with that allowance as possible. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been able to stretch company resources.", "\"I have recently implemented a schedule that allows for ride-sharing rewards which have cut down on our company's fuel expense by $9000 per month. I am quite proud of this initiative because it is not only financially responsible but also environmentally friendly.\"", "\"I am always looking for ways to reuse resources and cut back on spending. Most recently, I introduced a recycling program that rewarded our employees for making choices that re-purposed extra materials.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What type of work environment do you dislike working in?", "answers": ["Are you pretty flexible in your ability to work in most environments? Have you experienced a position where the atmosphere wasn't conducive to your productivity?  Be sure to know the type of situation offered in this position before the interview.", "\"I can be productive in most work environments, so long as the mentality is positive and teamwork is encouraged. I cannot work in an environment that feels negative or toxic.\"", "\"I have enjoyed my previous positions for the most part. I would say that if I were to feel dissatisfied with the job it would likely be due to lack of progress or working with a team that was uncommitted to success.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "Tell me about an error or mistake you made because of a breakdown in communication from you or one of your team members.", "answers": ["On occasion, mistakes will happen, and communication will be broken. Talk to the interviewer about a time that this occurred in the workplace. How did you resolve the situation?", "\"I recall one instance where I misread an email from one of my subordinates. The punctuation was incorrect, and I read it in in a dire tone rather than in a positive one, as it was intended. After a tense conversation, the employee clarified her intention, and it seems I was mistaken. She and I agreed to exercise verbal communication on a regular basis to avoid a similar situation from happening again.\"", "\"We recently had a missing link in communications to one of our vendors, who we signed on to provide a large service.  They were not aware of a change in the agreement which cost the company wasted time, resources and money.  We were able to identify the breakdown in communication and change the process to ensure it does not happen again.\""]}, {"topic": "Semiconductors", "question": "What are your weaknesses?", "answers": ["This question is a pervasive one, but it continues to throw people off. This question is not the best time to talk about your communication challenges with your partner or how you need to work on your golf game. Instead, focus on your professional life. \n\nWhat is a skill or quality that you are proactively working to improve? Whatever example you give, be sure that it is not a critical skill that will raise red flags to the employer. It's best to focus on a non-core skill when discussing your weaknesses.", "\"Although I am an Intermediate level user in Excel, I found that I was not up to date on some of the great functions offered by the program. I decided to enroll myself in an advanced Excel course. That course starts next week! I look forward to being an expert user soon.\"", "\"This is super cliche, but it's also true. I am not good at delegating to others. When I become submerged in a project, I don't like to give away any of the control. While this can be good, it can also definitely inhibit the outcome of the project and my growth as a team player and individual. I am currently working on this, as I know it is a deficit.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Have you ever broken a confidentiality agreement?", "answers": ["Companies will have confidentiality agreements for a variety of reasons. These could be to protect their trade secrets or to ensure that you do not bring clients over on the occasion that you leave their company. Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on confidentiality agreements.", "\"I never have, to my knowledge, broken a confidentiality agreement. Despite my reasons for leaving a position, I would never choose to hurt a previous employer in any way.\"", "\"A confidentiality agreement has never bound me; however, I would never knowingly break an agreement.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire leaders. Tell me about a time when you took the initiative to improve work related procedures.", "answers": ["Have you ever taken the opportunity to present your employer with potential change? Talk to the hiring manager about a time when you took the initiative in the workplace.", "\"I was able to present and implement one specific change in the office this past year. It was a recycling program that I felt was very important, even for our smaller office. We had significantly less waste after my initiative was implemented and I enjoyed seeing others take pride in helping our environment.\"", "\"I recently made suggestions to my manager about the team messaging application we were using. I found a team based app that offered a lower monthly cost, with added features. He took the suggestion, and it has worked well for our team! The company was happy with the cost savings as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with an education in computer science or another related field. Walk me through your post-secondary education and training.", "answers": ["The interviewer will likely have an idea of your education background from your resume. What they are asking is for you to take a few minutes to bring the experience to life for them! What was your major? Did you receive any special academic recognition? Discuss the strengths gained during your post-secondary training and how those skills will be used in your new position with Company ABC.", "\"I completed my Bachelor of Applied Technology from Carnegie Mellon University in 2004. During that time I specialized in Data Management and Analysis. I graduated with a 3.99 GPA, one of the top in my class.\"", "\"I recently completed my Diploma in Information Technology. I also have a great deal of on the job training and certifications, all listed on my resume. One of the biggest take-away's from my post-secondary experience was learning how to manage my time while working on multiple projects successfully. I perfected my multi-tasking skills and look forward to bringing those to work for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "If you could start your career over again, what direction would you take?", "answers": ["A hiring manager will be able to tell a lot about your personality by learning about your other career interests. If you could do anything over, what would you do, and why?", "\"I certainly do not regret the direction I have taken my career; however, if I had to start over in a new direction completely I would likely pursue my Degree in Education and become a teacher. Both of my parents were teachers, and they seemed to have a very fulfilling career. I enjoy coaching and leading others so, any tasks in my current career that related to these skills, are very welcome.\"", "\"I cannot even think of another career than the one that I have! If I had to choose, I would pursue a career in the arts so that I could continue to exercise my creative side.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Working at Company ABC, you will experience changes on a regular basis. When have you had to change a major component of your project due to new information being presented?", "answers": ["Being able to swivel the focus of your project is a necessary skill for your success in most careers. Talk to the interviewer about a time when a significant change occurred on a project. How did you handle the implementation of the new information?", "\"I had a large project last month that was nearly complete when the client called to say that the dimensions provided were incorrect. Because of this, our team had to re-do the entire proposal. It took us an additional four days of work but, in the end, the client was delighted with our work, and it resulted in new opportunities with them.\"", "\"I would say that being in the software and technology business means changing major components on projects on a very regular basis. I am very well accustomed to changing gears on a moment's notice and can adapt very well.\" (Give a recent example, if you are able)"]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "At Company ABC we take privacy and confidentiality very seriously. Are you willing to sign a non-disclosure agreement, if hired?", "answers": ["Signing a non-disclosure agreement is quite common in the software and technology industry. If hired, you will likely become privy to trade secrets, pending patents, and other innovative projects that must remain confidential. Talk to the interviewer about your willingness to sign an agreement. If you are currently under non-disclosure or non-compete agreement with your present employer, now is the time to discuss that.", "\"I have signed non-disclosure agreements in the past; although I am not currently under one. I see the importance of agreements such as this and am most willing to comply.\"", "\"I am happy to review any privacy and confidentiality agreements that you have.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Tell me about the most interesting project you have worked on this year and the biggest thing you learned from it.", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer one of your recent projects that particularly piqued your interest. Did it stretch you professionally? What was the biggest takeaway for you from that particular project?", "\"In my previous role we were working on a variety of projects with fingerprint recognition software. One of the most interesting projects was a fingerprint-based ATM system. It was a test project for a large banking institution. In addition to learning a great deal about fingerprint recognition, I was also able to learn a lot about the critical relationship between software and security.\"", "\"I find the majority of the projects that I have been working on this past year to be very interesting. If I had to choose one, I would choose to work on the Uber app. Since I am still in my internship, I didn't have any major contributions; however, I learned a lot about on-demand apps and building a friendly user interface.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "This role with Company ABC is highly technical. What is your understanding of this position and the responsibilities that come with it?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you bring a full understanding of the technical requirements attached to this particular job. It is essential that you research the role and thoroughly consume the information provided in the company's job posting/job description. Keep your answer to the point.", "\"From our previous conversation, understanding the job description, and researching the role online I feel that the job is best described as a project leader focused on X, Y, and Z. The technical requirements that you would like to see are A, B, and C. I am well versed in the tasks and programs you are asking for and am confident that I meet the strict requirements to perform in this role successfully.\"", "\"My understanding is that you seek a candidate with expert level skills in X, Y, and Z, who can train junior employees. I am an expert user in all three of these areas. Do you have any questions about my technical expertise?\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "What would you consider your technical specialty?", "answers": ["Do you have any particular areas of interest or ability? Talk to the interviewer about your strengths and be sure to highlight any specific skills that you excel in. It's a great idea, if you can, to highlight particular skills that may be listed on the company's job posting/job description. If there is a related area of interest where you'd like to expand your skills, you can mention those as well.", "\"Computing and Network Communications has always been a solid area for me. I have a big interest in how network communication improves our daily lives and our overall business efficiency. I see that you are looking for team members who are experts in network communications which is what caught my eye when I first saw your job posting.\"", "\"I have been focusing my career on becoming a cloud integration specialist although I do have cross-platform app development expertise as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "We seek to hire highly ambitious people. Where would you like your career with Company ABC take you?", "answers": ["Have you researched Company ABC enough to know how their internal hierarchy works? Do they have a variety of departments and management levels, offering you choices when it comes to carving out your career path? Talk to the interviewer about your career ambitions specifically related to this role and their organization.", "\"One of the reasons I was so excited to interview with Company ABC is because of the endless growth opportunities you appear to offer your high performing employees. My biggest ambition is to be awarded a management role in the next 3-5 years.\"", "\"What interests me most about your company is that there are so many options when it comes to career growth. Ideally, I would like to earn my way into a team lead role, then a division manager position in the digital management department. Eventually, a CDO (Chief Data Officer) level role would be ideal. Of course, I understand that this will take many years of dedication and hard work.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "In your opinion, what has been the biggest advancement in technology this past year?", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you have an invested interest in the technology industry by discussing your thoughts on recent advancements. Be sure to include how you stay up to date on industry changes and new technology.", "\"There have been so many great advancements in technology this year. Recently, I was reading an article by MIT Technology Review and was amazed at the incredible advancements this year. The one that stood out most to me was the autopilot software update released by Tesla this year. We truly will have the software for vehicles to be controlled by tech rather than humans.\"", "\"The most impressive advancement in technology, in my opinion, is the continued advancement of mobile integration. Tech connects most of the modern world, and we can do absolutely everything from our phones these days.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "At Company ABC we take pride in our ability to stay one step ahead of our competitors. How will you contribute to this trend?", "answers": ["It is critical that you research Company ABC and their most vigorous competitors, before your interview. What does Company ABC do best, and who is trying to do it better? Speak openly with the interviewer about your ability to work competitively and how you plan to contribute to their continued success.", "\"I believe the best way to stay ahead of your competitors is to pay a big amount of attention to the fine details. When you put out a great product, others will try to mimic your work, but they will cut corners because they will feel rushed to get it out on the marketplace first. I will contribute to the success of Company ABC by committing my most attentive work to you every day.\"", "\"I think that the best way to stay ahead of competitors is to keep your projects as simple as possible while remaining innovative. People want simple, easy products, which they can understand. What I've seen from my competitors lately is that they overcomplicate their products. I offer clean and consistent work that your buyers would relate to.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Looking at our products and services, what do you think we do better at Company ABC than any of our competitors?", "answers": ["Before your interview, be sure to research Company ABC and any awards or recognition they have recently received. In their industry, and competitive space, where do they stand out? Be sure to speak positively about the organization's recent achievements to show that you are interested and engaged in their work.", "\"When I was preparing for this interview I noticed that Company ABC was recently recognized for innovation in XYZ. You are a trailblazer in this particular arena which is amazing.\"", "\"After reading reviews on your company, I believe that your reputation is the most solid and sincere of all your competitors. Amazing service is always the best way to stand out.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "We consider research to be the backbone of what we do at Company ABC. Do you think it's important to conduct research before beginning a project or would you rather jump right in?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your work habits and the way in which you prefer to approach a new project. If you have a sense of how Company ABC prefers to approach their work you should discuss that method. For instance, if the interviewer tells you that they prefer extensive research before beginning a project, that is your queue to talk about your excellent research skills.", "\"I agree that research is the backbone of a strong project. Without it, important details are missed and much time is wasted. I like to research before starting a project so that I can lay out a plan and understand the potential hurdles as well.\"", "\"Although there are some instances where jumping right it may be required, I always prefer to research before I being a project. Rest assured; I would always follow your preferred methods, should I be hired.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "I would like to have a full understanding of your experience and portfolio. What types of industries have your previous projects been involved in?", "answers": ["The software and technology industry is all-encompassing, and it is essential for the interviewer to have a full understanding of the sectors and types of projects in which you bring experience. Be sure to highlight any projects or clients mainly related to Company ABC as that may pique the interviewer's interest!", "\"I have experience in a wide range of industries including healthcare, automotive, and education. Most notably, I have worked with organizations similar to yours including Company ABC and Company XYZ.\"", "A great alternative to explaining your projects is to bring a substantial portfolio with you. \"I wanted to show you a full range of my experience, so I have brought you a digital portfolio of my work. Would you like to take a look?\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Tell me about your greatest work related accomplishment.", "answers": ["Talking about your most significant accomplishment will give the interviewer a firm idea of where you place your values. It will also show the interviewer more about your personality, how you like to be motivated, and how to coach you in the future. It is okay to brag a little bit when answering this question. Show that you are proud of yourself and your career accomplishments!", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This accomplishment showed me that I could dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and be recognized for my dedication.\"", "\"My greatest work-related accomplishment was the management promotion I received at Company X after just one year. I worked very hard for that promotion and was so happy when my work and dedication was rewarded. It kick-started my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "At Company ABC we value organization. Tell us about a time when you were particularly effective on prioritizing tasks and completing a project on schedule.", "answers": ["An interviewer needs to hear that you have a plan in place to keep yourself organized.  Start off by mentioning that you are typically an organized person.  From here, dive into a recent time-consuming project that you were involved with.  \n\nYou might say, 'I recently was involved with a project that required 30 hours of my time in a two week period while I was also in the middle of several other projects.'  \n\nTell the interviewer that you started off by ensuring you had your schedule mapped out before you dove into your workload. Discuss if you made a to-do list, updated your calendar, or created a color-coded agenda. Share whatever organization method worked for you! Next, tell the interviewer how you prioritized the work. You may share that each day you sat down to determine the urgent needs for that day and marked them with a letter A. Perhaps you identified anything that would be nice to get done that day with a letter B. And, maybe you just left everything else that could wait for another day unmarked. Tell the interviewer how you diligently stuck with this plan for the duration of the project and how it allowed you to complete the project on time without any stress successfully.", "\"Last week I was asked to lead our team while our manager was away. I created a checklist of things that needed to be completed to reach our deadlines. I gathered the team to discuss our goals and asked for input and ideas to get us there. It was a great experience for me because not only was I able to exercise my leadership capabilities; I was also able to learn more about prioritizing, from my team.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Who would you say inspires you?", "answers": ["Your life's inspiration can come from a book, a mentor, your family, a celebrity, author - literally anyone! Talk to the interviewer about who has inspired your life and why.", "\"I find inspiration in a variety of people and things. I would have to say that the person who has most greatly inspired me has been my grandmother. She always had a smile on her face no matter how hard she worked and she loved everyone. She was well respected and always gave more than she received. I try to live like her as much as I can.\"", "\"I am continually inspired by the books that I read! Whether it is the author, or the characters themselves, I love to get lost in a good novel for inspiration.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "What experience do you have using team-based messaging applications?", "answers": ["There are many options for communication software and messaging applications. Give the interviewer a brief overview of the apps you are experienced in and assure them that you can learn their internal system, should it be new to you.", "\"I have used a variety of team-based messaging applications. I am best versed in Brosix, AOL Instant Messenger, and Freedcamp. No matter which system you use I am sure that I can pick it up very quickly.\"", "\"Although I have not worked with a team based messaging application, I am confident that I would learn very quickly. Which team based messaging apps do you use at Company ABC? I would love to get a head start and begin learning.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "Culture fit is important to us at Company ABC. How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. This answer could include buzzwords such as introverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "Try to include a variety of words that the interviewer does not hear all the time. Be unique! Here are some ideas: \n\n- Adaptable\n- Considerate\n- Diligent \n- Intuitive\n- Persistent\n- Resourceful\n- Sincere\n- Witty"]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "We encourage innovation at Company ABC. When have you created a new product or service?", "answers": ["Using your creative mind, have you ever introduced an employer to a new product or service opportunity? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have created a new product or service.", "\"In my previous role I was fortunate enough to introduce my company to the idea of a gold level service where, in addition to our general customer service, we added on service options. Our customer base responded very positively, and we kept the program running for a few years.\"", "\"In my current position, I create new products and services nearly every week! The most recent product that I created was X. Our customers received it well, and we are continuing to expand on the product now.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "What do you think you will like about this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear what you are looking forward to learning and experiencing in this new position. Talk about what excites you! Share how this position will challenge you and help you grow. New opportunities are a chance for you to demonstrate your skills.", "\"I look forward to helping companies by analyzing data that will help them make solid decisions surrounding their digital future.\"", "\"I am looking forward to getting more experience in UI, and feel that Company ABC is the best place for me. You have a great reputation for creating beautiful and easy to use products.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "How do you keep up-to-date on new technologies and trends in this industry?", "answers": ["One way that a potential employer will gauge 'fit' is by ensuring that you are passionate about your particular industry. Show the interviewer that you are passionate about your industry by openly discussing how you stay on top of industry trends.", "\"I keep up to date on new technologies and trends through a variety of sources. I follow three different blogs from industry leaders as well as read multiple articles online per week.\"", "\"I keep up on new trends in this industry by taking additional coursework online, whenever possible. I also follow a few of my favorite influencers on social media.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"I consider a project a success only when I have produced work that I can be proud of.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "We want to hire people at Company ABC who have the desire to lead others. How many people did you supervise at your last position?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer your level of responsibility in your current position. If you have managed larger teams than you currently are, you can also discuss that particular role from your work history.", "\"Currently, I am supervising 12 employees with an overall portfolio responsibility of $24MM. In my role, before this one, I managed 23 employees but with a smaller portfolio of $6MM. I can handle a large range of employees.\"", "\"Although I did not officially supervise anyone in my most recent position, I always had my eye out for opportunities to lead or mentor the more junior staff.\""]}, {"topic": "Software+and+Technology", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $66,000 per year plus health benefits. I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am looking for a base salary of $68-72,000 in my next position.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "If you were hired today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, about sales targets in this position, you mentioned that most new sales professionals hit their KPI's after 120 days. If hired today, my goal would be to exceed my KPI's after the first 90 days. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would start with analyzing all quantifiable data from the last month, quarter, and year to identify any bottlenecks or shortfalls and set a plan to correct them.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What anti-virus programs have you used, and have you ever had difficulty installing them?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know your scope of understanding when it comes to different anti-virus programs, the problems that can arise, and the importance of cyber-security. Briefly discuss the anti-virus programs that you have used/installed.", "\"Effective cybersecurity solutions are incredibly important. I've used many different anti-virus software. Norton and AVG are my go-to. They're large, well-known brands. Installation is simple and straightforward. They also have extensive libraries of information if you do run into difficulty.\"", "\"For my residential clients, I usually suggest AVG. For my commercial clients, my go-to program is Avast Endpoint Protection Advanced. The installation has always been simple for me as both offerings include great step-by-step guides as well as a 24/7 customer support.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "We are looking for a long term fit. What are your short-term and long-term career goals with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that there is a strong alignment between what Company ABC is offering and what you are looking for in a long-term fit. Discuss your ideal career situation, short and long-term.", "\"My immediate goal is to find employment with a company who values and rewards a strong work ethic, a creative mind, and a desire for innovation. I am seeking a role with a company where I can continue to grow and refine my skills. In the more distant future, I'm interested in exploring leadership opportunities. From my research, I believe that Company ABC is a strong fit for my short and long-term career goals.\"", "\"One short-term goal that I have set for myself is to take a Telecom Fraud and Telecom Billing workshop. This additional training will be a stepping stone to my long-term goal of working in an auditing type of role within the telecommunications industry. I am looking to join an organization that can support these goals, and I believe that Company ABC is the fit that I have been looking for.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Tell us about your experience in telecommunications.", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for an answer that highlights your comprehensive industry experience. Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your related education, passion, and enthusiasm for the telecommunications industry.", "\"My passion for telecommunications comes from a love of computers. I've worked with computers, building them and deconstructing them, since my teenage years. After I finished school, I went to college and completed a degree in computer science. Since graduating, I've worked as a Telecommunications Specialist. I love this work as it's full of challenges and problems to solve. It provides me with the opportunity to learn something new every day.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my diploma in Telecommunications Technology, with a focus on computer applications. I completed a 3-month internship this summer with (Company ABC), and I am now looking for my first true employment opportunity in the telecommunications industry. I am excited about this potential role with Company ABC because it will offer me the chance to grow my career with a well-respected organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Workers in the telecommunications industry often spend a lot of time on the road and doing off-site work. This means you don't see colleagues regularly. How do you develop trust among your team members when working remotely?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know you are aware of the challenges that come with a role that requires travel. Show that you are proactive and deliberate in forming relationships with your colleagues despite being on the road.", "\"It can be difficult to build relationships, particularly trust when you're not in each other's company often. I've found that putting in additional effort, responding to questions and comments in online channels, sending nice messages of congratulations when good work is done, or remembering birthdays, etc. is a good way to build relationships and trust.\"", "\"I develop trust among my co-workers by showing them that I am reliable, trustworthy, and a hard worker. Showing someone your work ethic is the strongest way to build trust, in my opinion.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "When have you given back to the community?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like further insight into how altruistic you are. Give the interviewer at Company ABC a deeper insight into your values by discussing the ways that you give back. Perhaps you volunteer at a local charity, donate a portion of your paycheck to a specific organization, clean up around the parks on the weekend, or help your family with their needs. Be sure to use a recent example as you do not want to lean on volunteer experience from 12 years ago.", "\"Being an active participant in my community is second nature to me. There are a lot of people who are much less fortunate than I am and it's important for me to set a good example for my kids. When I was younger, I loved to travel, particularly in South East Asia where I volunteered with Habitat for Humanity. More recently I support my kids to sponsor a child. I also think it's great that Company ABC has volunteer days for staff to give back to the community. It's one of the things that attracted me to your organization.\"", "\"I believe in the importance of giving back so, for that reason, I spend every other Friday evening volunteering at our local soup kitchen. I was raised to believe in the importance of volunteerism. Does Company ABC have a volunteer committee in place? If not, this is something that I would be very interested in heading up one day.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["Is honesty always the best policy? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"Honesty is always the best policy.  Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message so managing this with each situation is critical to building honest and trustworthy relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one-sided hunt. You must also feel as though this is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer about your ideal employer. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "\"My ideal employer is one that allows me to take the reigns when it comes to problem-solving. I like to be hands-on and prefer to work for people who value this in me.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What type of work environment allows you to be the most productive?", "answers": ["Are you able to be productive in any environment? Are there particular types of situations that you find distracting? Discuss your preferences with the interviewer. Be sure to research the kind of environment offered in this position before the interview.", "\"I understand that your work environment is very collaborative. I come from a similar environment and found that I could be very productive when there was the \"", "\"I work well in a high pressure, demanding environment that requires you to work smart and make your mark. I am competitive in nature and love to be challenged on a personal and professional level.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Tell me about a time that you have helped a co-worker accomplish an important goal.", "answers": ["Being goal-oriented and determined is imperative. What do you do, outside of your own goals, to ensure that everyone on your team is successful? Assure the interviewer that you are always willing to keep the team, or company as a whole, in mind.", "\"As a Sales Manager my team is only as successful as the lowest producing employee. It is critical that my entire team is motivated, engaged, and on point with their KPIs. Last month I hired a new employee who was struggling significantly with sales. I sat him down and realized that he didn't understand the product. We spent a few hours together over that next week learning the product. In the end, his sales increased by 64%, and he was significantly more confident. It helped the team morale as well.\"", "\"When a new hire starts, I have become the go-to for shadowing. I always make sure to introduce myself to a brand new employee in my same role, and rather than see him or her as a threat, I schedule time for him or her to sit down with me and shadow what I do and how I do it. I want to see everyone succeed and, since there is no real training program in our company, I feel I need to be the change maker in the organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Which coding languages are you familiar with?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for evidence of continued learning and improvement. Your desire and willingness to expand your knowledge into different areas of technology is something that will make you a stand out candidate. Discuss the coding languages you are most familiar with and be sure to ask the interviewer if they are looking for any specific coding languages. You want to have the opportunity to address any potential shortcomings in your experience right away.", "\"I began my current position with very minimal coding skills. I can confidently say that I now have intermediate coding skills - primarily in HTML, CSS and more recently, JavaScript. I'm largely self-taught and started to learn as a hobby to build digital systems on the weekend. I've noticed over the last five years that this knowledge is becoming particularly valuable in my day-to-day work. Are there any coding languages you are specifically looking for?\"", "\"Coding has not been the primary focus of my training. With that said, I have worked with individuals who are fluent in CSS and JavaScript. Are there any coding languages that you need me to learn, to be successful in this role? I am happy to take any required coursework.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Tell us about a time when you successfully installed new or modified software, hardware or programming modules.", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for specific technical knowledge. Be sure to answer specifically and demonstrate your full understanding of these technical tasks.", "\"During college, I completed a couple of jobs for friends who had small business requirements. One client was looking for a solution to manage contacts and client information as he was using only a manual spreadsheet. I researched appropriate CMS platforms and advised him on what I thought would best suit his needs. I then went through a mapping process, understanding what he needed the software to do. I customized fields which required basic coding skills, and provided process guides for how he should best use the software going forward.\"", "\"Not too long ago I had to do a company-wide Windows 10 installation for one of our clients. I planned the installation with my team; we briefed all 50 employees on what to expect during the installation, and how long we expected the install to take. The project ran seamlessly, and I believe this was because we communicated so clearly along the way with all parties.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "At Company ABC we put a lot of effort into staying 'in-the-know' within our industry. How do you keep up-to-date with new technology and trends?", "answers": ["There is no right or wrong answer! You merely want to display to the interviewer that you have a finger on the pulse of what is happening in the telecommunications industry. Briefly discuss how you stay up-to-date on new industry related trends. It's a great idea to ask the interviewer what their favorite resources are, as well. This question could open up a great conversation!", "\"I spend a lot of time reading different websites such as CNET, Wired, and Techcrunch. Those are some of my favorites. New technology develops so fast, so I agree that it is essential to keep up-to-date. What are your favorite industry resources?\"", "\"I listen to a lot of industry related podcasts and also have a few Google alerts set up so that I can get instant notifications on buzz-worthy changes and trends. I am always keeping an eye out for new information sources. Which are your favorites?\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire those who are collaborative by nature. How do you get along in a team based environment?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like for you to demonstrate that you can work well in a team-based and collaborative environment. Use a real-life example from a time when you have worked in a team based environment.", "\"I love working in a team-based environment. I enjoy bouncing ideas off others and the camaraderie that comes with being part of a high functioning team. As a Telecommunications Specialist, there are many times where I'm required to work alone, troubleshooting a technical problem off-site. I've received feedback from previous managers who have noted I'm particularly malleable and can work well independently and as part of a team.\"", "\"Whether I am doing an independent project, or working in a team environment, I always give my best. I enjoy the camaraderie of working in a team, but I can be successful working autonomously as well.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Why should we hire you to work at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer how your skills, experience, and education relate to the job for which you are being considered. The interviewer wants to see that you have read, and understand the position description, and that you have an understanding of the workplace culture at Company ABC.", "\"I have over a dozen years of experience in the industry at one of your largest competitors. I have a proven track record of successes there and will bring that knowledge, not only of the industry but also of my creative solutions and how to position our department better against theirs and help elevate your business to the next level. Having been a part of the industry for nearly half of my life, I have seen a ton of change and have adapted to every change or innovation with ease and excitement, and I look forward to doing that at your company as well.\"", "\"You should hire me because I am unlike anyone else you have interviewed before. When I started with my current company, I was the youngest salesperson they had ever hired. That didn't stop me from becoming the #1 sales person in the company within six months. I am dedicated to my craft and engaged in this industry to the point where I commit myself to taking at least one business development or leadership related workshop every business quarter. I am a competitive achiever. You won't be disappointed when you hire me.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Describe your knowledge of Agile project management. How does it differ to other project management methodologies?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to see that your knowledge is strong enough that you can compare project management methodologies. Discuss your current knowledge of Agile project management.", "\"Most of the projects I've been part of have used Agile methodology. In my opinion, Agile project management gives greater flexibility to pivot without requiring substantial changes and reworking. The risk is also reduced as the project is completed in iterative steps, with testing along the way, rather than waiting until the end of the project.\"", "\"I have not been part of many projects that use the Agile methodology so my understanding could be stronger than it currently is.  From my understanding, Agile encourages more of a collaborative environment with faster response time.  In my current position, we more often utilize XPM, Extreme Project Management. This choice is because many of our projects are short with a tight deadline and XPM is most effective for those types of project plans.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What do you know about Company ABC?", "answers": ["Your answer should demonstrate that you have done your research on Company ABC and have an understanding of the challenges Company ABC faces, the goals they're trying to achieve, and the market in which the company operates.", "\"I've always been inspired by what Company ABC has achieved. The remarkable growth and the overwhelmingly positive press has always made Company ABC stand out in the telecommunications industry. I know that you have been in business for XX years and that you've seen an XX% growth in the past 18 months due to your innovation and focus on a progressive culture. I am excited to work with such a progressive company.\"", "\"Your company has an impressive industry reputation, and I would be thrilled to learn from your leadership team. From my research, I find that you are very involved in the community and put a lot of efforts into developing your employees.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants assurance that your values align with the values and vision of Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that this role would be a progressive step in your career and be sure to express your excitement!", "\"I have always appreciated the values at Company ABC and the way you treat your customers. Company ABC shows consistency in branding and your commitment to putting the customer first is a rare find. This commitment is very much in line with my customer service philosophy and the type of culture I am looking for in my next opportunity.\"", "\"I am impressed by your mission, and I love how much of an impact you make on the local community. Winning the community Humanitarian Award in 2016 was a remarkable achievement that stands out to me. In addition to all of this, I want to work for your company because you offer the growth, development, and leadership opportunities for which I have been looking. I see a long-term fit here which is important to me.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Tell me about recent courses or training you've completed in your role as a Telecommunications Technician.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like for you to demonstrate your desire for continuous learning. Discuss how you have expanded your knowledge since starting a career in Telecommunications.", "\"Recently I've wanted to improve my managerial and leadership skills so I can take that next step in my career. In my early career, I focused a lot on developmental activities that would increase my technical knowledge. Over the last year, I've found a senior manager to mentor me in developing my leadership skills. I've also completed an internal adaptive leadership program through my current organization to develop these skills and knowledge further.\"", "\"I have not been given the opportunity to attend any additional coursework or training since starting with my current company. This lack of opportunity is one of the reasons why I seek a new position. I appreciate that Company ABC sees value in continuous education.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Why did you choose to become a Telecommunication Technician?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see your passion and enthusiasm for a profession in the telecommunications industry. Talk about what led you to a career in telecommunications and what helps you to find fulfillment in your day to day work.", "\"I wasn't sure what I wanted to do when I completed high school. From a young age, I always liked being active. I knew I would find an office job mundane. A school counselor suggested an apprenticeship with a local telecommunications company, and I've never looked back. Since starting my career in telecommunications, I've loved the variety of work, different challenges, and interacting with many different people to solve their ICT problems.\"", "\"My initial interest in this line of work came from my older brother who was also a telecommunications technician. I took a couple of courses at our local college and found it interesting. After completing that coursework, I decided to dive in and get my degree in computer science. Being a Technician is an exciting goal for me, and I hope to start this career path with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What was the biggest change you have had to deal with in your career?", "answers": ["You will likely face change in your career from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you can adapt to significant changes in a professional manner.", "\"The biggest change that I have faced in my career so far would be when my previous company went through a major merger. We had to adapt to new processes and management which was quite challenging. In the end, it worked out well for the company, in a financial perspective, so the changes were well worth the challenges we faced initially.\"", "\"The biggest challenge I have had to deal with in my career was the economic recession that hit almost immediately after I graduated with my degree. It was incredibly difficult to find a job in my related field. Not wanting to stay idle, I chose to take on an unpaid internship in my field to not become redundant. It was a smart choice in the end because, after three months of interning, I was offered a full time, permanent position with that organization. It was a grind, and I learned a lot during that time about patience and endurance.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "We work hard to keep a harmonious workplace culture at Company ABC. Have you ever had a conflict with a manager? How did you resolve it?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how you react to a conflict situation, and how active you are in attempting resolution. Use a real-life example if you can. If you are newer to your career, this could include a case of a conflict with a professor (perhaps you disagreed with a grade you received). How you behave in a conflict situation will be critical information for the interviewer.", "\"Nobody enjoys conflict in the workplace; however, I have experienced it before. In my previous position, there was a miscommunication with my manager with my work schedule. He accidentally scheduled me on my requested day off, and I felt disrespected. I reacted faster than I should have because once we discussed it, I realized he made an honest mistake. I am a firm believer that with mutual respect, conflicts can resolve. I learned to slow my reaction time.\"", "The interviewer wants to know that you are capable of maintaining a harmonious relationship with those who are considered your leaders. If your relationship with your boss wasn't amazing, what efforts did you take to make it better? Here are some suggestions: \n\n- Try to understand what your boss values the most\n- Keep your cool, even when you want to lose it\n- Anticipate their needs and stay one step ahead\n- Take leadership opportunities to show your worth\n- Adapt to their preferences"]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Excellent customer service is very important to us at Company ABC. How do you handle challenging customers?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you remain professional, helpful, and calm when dealing with customers of all kinds. If you can, give a specific example of a time when you successfully assisted a challenging customer.", "\"As a Telecommunications Specialist, I'm often called out to assist customers who are frustrated, disappointed or angry due to equipment failure. In these situations, I always listen first, then validate the customer's feelings before jumping to solutions. Technical disruptions can be frustrating, and I want them to know I am on their side. Once the customer feels heard, I then begin troubleshooting the issue and working to resolve it. I won't leave a service call until I know the customer is delighted.\"", "\"Challenging customers are present in any industry, and I have experienced a wide range of them in my career, so far. I find that upset customers just feel like their problems are not heard. By offering an empathetic ear to their situation, I can usually diffuse the situation immediately. I will ask them what they feel a suitable solution is and then provide that solution, or as close to it as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "How can Company ABC continue to perform better than our competitors?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how well you understand the industry, and the business environment that Company ABC operates in. Showcase the research you have conducted on Company ABC and their competitors.", "\"I believe Company ABC has continued to be an industry leader due to its unwavering commitment to quality, their customers, and persistent innovation. Some telecommunications companies have fallen behind because they are focused on what competitors are doing, instead of focusing on true and unique innovation. Developing products and solutions that customers want is what is important, and I believe that Company ABC has mastered that.\"", "\"I believe that the key to outperforming your competitor is in knowing the needs and wants of your customers better than they do. I have seen the quality and satisfaction surveys that Company ABC conducts as well as the regular customer check-points to ensure overall happiness. I think that this can be even stronger by adding more touch-points and places for customers to leave feedback.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What do you know about our customers and the target market at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for clues that you understand who their clientele is, and what their requirements might be. Show the interviewer that you know their business and target market. It is okay to ask the interviewer more about their target market. Anything they share will you will help you in the next interview!", "\"From what I understand, Company ABC offers solutions and products to residential and small-business customers. As evidenced in the case studies Company ABC has released, there is a large focus on Company ABC being a community partner. Access to reliable, high-speed internet is a particular challenge facing this part of the country, and it's exciting to see a company committed to tackling this problem for the residential and small business community who do not have large budgets. Is there anything specific you would like to share with me about your customers and target market?\"", "\"I've been a customer for several years, and so I know you're looking to make your products and services accessible, understandable, and affordable to people just like me. I think that's such a great mission and Company ABC is doing a great job of getting the attention of this target market.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Would you say you focus more on reasons why change will not work rather than adapting to new changes?", "answers": ["When a change occurs in the workplace do you view it positively or do you resist the change? Talk to the interviewer about how you adapt to change.", "\"When a change occurs in the workplace I initially try to balance the pros and the cons before reacting. Overall I would say that I prefer to focus on why the changes will work. I am a positive person by nature.\"", "\"I am happy to adapt to changes as long as they make sense and help with productivity. I am a team player and will always choose the positive side of things rather than dwelling on the potential difficulties.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Have you ever taken a role in a company that hasn't fit into your long-term career plans?", "answers": ["Most people have taken on a position that was not a fit for them in the end. It's best to openly discuss any jobs that you have held that were not a fit. This information will assist the interviewer in being able to place you within their organization correctly. Be sure to end your answer on a positive note, discussing how you bounced back from the misstep.", "\"Yes, you will see that from March to May 2007 I held a role as Executive Business Development Manager with Company XYZ. This particular role was not what I was expecting and had little to do with management and more to do with cold calling onto C-suite level clients. This activity wasn't nurturing my plan to grow the management side of my career, so I resigned after just two months. Luckily I landed a wonderful job immediately after and grew with that company for the following six years.\"", "\"I have not taken a position merely to have a job. I am cautious who I work for and am happy that my discretion has worked well for me and my career path.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "When have you worked among a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable, and happy, in this type of environment because it offers a great learning opportunity.\"", "\"In my current role, I work alongside cross-functional teams regularly. Together, we manage our business and effectiveness.\""]}, {"topic": "Telecommunications", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"Yes, I am actively seeking a new opportunity in the telecommunications industry. With that said, I am very choosy on where I apply as my next role needs to be a smart step in my career.\""]}]